And when I read the white paper, I copy
pasted an exact like payload
from that PDF and it exploited
everything on
>> Akami.
[Music]
Best part of acting when you can just,
you know, critical think, right?
Yeah, dude.
[Music]
All right, sub hackers. We got the tw
for this week, the this weekend bug
bounty for this week. There we go. Uh,
just two articles that I wanted to kind
of bring to y'all's attention. First up
is Yes, We Hack has released a monster
of a guide on setting up your uh Android
Bug Bounty Lab essentially. Um, and they
cover a bunch of stuff in here.
Obviously, they cover the basics, but I
just wanted to highlight a couple things
for you. One, they break down what kind
of mobile device, uh, you know, like
emulator that you should be using. And
as I was kind of reading through this, I
I did not know this, but um, let's see
if I can find the port portion of it. Uh
apparently, yeah, there's ARM
translation in uh Android emulator and
it's just for the apps. Okay, so here's
what it says. The new Android 11 system
images are capable of translating ARM
instructions to x86 without impacting
the entire system. This allows execution
of ARM binaries for testing without the
performance overhead of full ARM
emulation. So you can still run your
system image in x86 but run ARM uh apps
via this ARM translation for Android
emulator. So uh that is massive uh and
really helps with the performance issues
that you'll see in a lot of Android
emulators. Um was really cool to see
that. And then they give a really
in-depth um summary of how to set up,
you know, all of these various
emulators, um which one you should be
using, how to route a physical device if
you need to actually do that with um uh
Magisk and um and then they also talk
about proxying um the the traffic
through uh Burp and they also talk about
uh bypassing uh SSL pinning with Freda.
So it's a very like comprehensive write
up here. Um definitely worth checking
out. I think this is probably like the
go-to article on like getting your uh
Bug Bounty mobile lab set up, which not
enough of you have done apparently
because we did a promotion with Adobe um
where we were highlighting mobile apps
and very few submissions came through
from the critical thinkers. Um so guys,
if you are tired of getting dupes and
you want to build a unique skill set,
then you really should go read this, set
up your mobile testing environment and
just b do basic API testing on mobile
apps and you'll find a lot of bugs. Um,
really cool stuff. The only thing I
wanted to add to this uh was that they
are pushing where's the like proxy
section? Here it is right here. They
push the proxy configuration like this,
which is totally fine. Um, but I I also
really like to use ADB to create a um to
open up sort of a pipe from the actual
device itself to my local host uh on on
my host machine, right? Uh in these
emulators. So then you can just point uh
the ADB um proxy at localhost on the mo
the mobile device and it'll just proxy
through to Burp or Kaido or whatever
you're using on the outside. So um yeah,
look into that technique as well. I
think Joel mentioned it on one of the
episodes a while back. Um and apparently
today is mobile day because we also have
a uh a write up here from Bug Crowd uh
mobile hacking resource kit, your
onestop shop for iOS and Android um pen
testing. So, inside of this kit, they
have a PDF that kind of talks about all
of the valuable resources that you'll
need. Um, videos, courses, blog posts,
tools, that sort of thing. Um, and kind
of has them all in a nice list. So, if
you're ready to take the the mobile deep
dive, you know, check out this list
right here. Check out the Yes, We Hack
write up from before. Um, and then
here's the PDF that sort of comes along
with that. It just kind of has like a a
quick resource kit um for mobile
hacking. um and deep dive these two
resources and then you'll be really well
set for for mobile hacking. Um all
right, that's what we had on this
weekend bug bounty segment. Let's get
into the show.
All right, cool. Well, James, this is uh
this is the moment I've been waiting for
since I started this podcast uh that I
finally get to have the god of research,
the legendary James Kettle. So, thank
you so much for joining today, man.
>> Thanks. It's a honor to be here. I've
been looking forward to this for a
while. Yeah, dude. I'm sorry about the
cancellations and stuff, too. I feel so
bad because I was telling James before
the episode, uh, you know, off air, we
never cancel like on our side. We are
very consistent, you know, with critical
thinking podcast. And I just got so sick
the day that he was supposed to come on
and I was like, I can't I can't do it.
And I had to had to cancel on him. So,
thanks for being flexible about the
timing, too, James.
Um, all right. So, let's let's I can't
believe I'm saying this, but you know,
rules are rules, James. So, uh you know,
whenever we have a researcher or a
technical person on the podcast, we have
them sort of give us a bug, right, to to
the audience to prove their their stuff.
So, James Kettle, head of research at
Portswiger Research, please prove your
worth to the community by sharing a bug,
please.
>> Okay. Absolutely. So,
>> I found this quite a tricky question.
There's a lot of uh there's a lot of
bugs that I'd love to share, but uh I'm
going to share one that was a personal
favorite for me and is maybe a bit
possibly underrated maybe. Um so this is
Where's the CV? I wrote this down
somewhere. Here we are. CVE 2022 22720.
This is a pausebased
man-in-the-middle powered
client side desync affecting Apache
HTTPD. Uh
>> oh my gosh,
>> this thing this thing is is super cool.
Uh it's got all the great elements of a
of a research grade finding. So I found
the issue
the like I found the attack technique of
pause based by accident. I tried to
enforce a like a 2cond timeout when I
was scanning thousands of bug bounty
sites and there was a bug. So the
timeout was actually like 15 seconds.
And of those 30,000 different websites,
there was one website that was
vulnerable to a pausebased desync and
had a custom 10-second timeout. Uh, as
an aside, this is a great example of why
scanning VDPs can be super valuable
because that site didn't actually pay
bounties, but I would have never have
discovered the entire attack class if it
wasn't for that one website. Um, but
anyway, having found that, that was on
varnish. But then when I realized this
was a thing, I went scanning with an
even higher timeout and found that the
pausebased desync technique, which is
where you start to send a request and
you send the headers and then you just
wait and you wait and wait and wait and
eventually you get a server timeout
response and then what you send after
that is interpreted by the server as the
next request even though technically
speaking you haven't finished the first
request. So I found if you waited for 60
seconds that technique worked on Apache.
Now exploiting exploiting this is super
difficult in practice because if you
want to use it for a classic serverside
desync Apache needs to be behind a front
end server which has a timeout of over
60 seconds which is relatively rare. And
then there's this horrendous race
condition as well which makes it really
nasty. Uh but I had another thought
which was well how can you make this
work as a client site desync so when
there's no intermediary
server
and it got me thinking about
man-in-the-middle attacks. So this is
something I I think bug bounty hunters
probably don't look at think about
man-in-the-middle stuff very frequently.
Uh, I haven't heard of anyone like
making a great living in bug bounty by
specializing in attacks that require a
man in the middle, but
but my experience has shown that some
companies actually do care about this a
lot. It basically depends on their
threat model. Uh, for example, ages ago,
like maybe 2009
or something, uh, I found a bug in
Firefox where they accidentally
whitelisted a development URL and I
said, "You've got a vulnerability.
You've whitelisted some random Mozilla
dev's personal server and I can probably
pone the server and then get code
execution." And they were like, "No, no,
no. don't believe you can pone the
server, but because it's a HTTP URL and
you could do a man in the middle, we'll
pay you for it. And they pay me the same
amount as finding like a SQL injection
in one of websites because Masilla,
Firefox, like their threat model
>> is governments, right? There are
governments that will p their users
using man-in-the-middle attacks um or
monster in the middle or whatever
they're called these days. Um, so, so
that made me think, hang on, Apache
probably actually do care about a
man-in-the-middle attack. And in theory,
if an attacker just pauses a request at
the right moment, they should be able to
do this on the encrypted connection. In
theory, like I remember some research
from about 15 years ago where someone
was some academic research showed that
if you looked at the TLS packet sizes
that someone was was seeing, you could
fingerprint them and basically work out
which page on a website they were
loading just by guesswork basically.
>> Wow. Uh, and so to investigate that, I
basically had two weeks spare and I knew
the theory could work. And then I had to
like set up boxes, set up a man in the
middle, like this is way outside my
comfort zone. I had no idea what I was
doing. It took me ages just to set up
and uh set up a a box to proxy the
traffic through a different box like
with IP tables. And then I thought I
could use like laggy network simulation
software to cause the delay necessary
for the desync. But it didn't work at
the right level. So I had to look up
this stuff called
Qisk, which I still don't understand.
And this was before AI, so I couldn't
get chat GVD to do it all for me.
>> Uh, and it was like it was just mega
outside my comfort zone. I set up the
firewall wrong. and I cut and I blocked
off my own I ended up delaying my own
SSH connection traffic. So whenever I
typed something, it took over 60 seconds
to actually to actually get to the
server. Uh it was a massive mess, but I
got it working in in the end. And it it
was it was super cool just to go from
that concept and spend two weeks on this
one thing and prove, yeah, this is
actually possible. I I broke I briefly
broke TLS on on Apache.
>> It was super cool
>> and it even set me up uh the other
valuable thing was it set me up for
understanding that kind of lower level
network level stuff and I think it's
part of what led to the development of
the single packet attack which uses HB2
to find race conditions and timing
attacks better. And I I think that's
like one of the nicest features that
we've got in Burpu right now. I'm super
happy with that.
>> Yeah, dude. I think the single packet
attack like you obviously like we were
saying before your your research list
that I had to go through for this
episode was just massive. The single
packet attack is like one of the most
amazing like just principles that I
think has come out of your research.
It's just very nice.
>> It is super cool. Yeah. And what I loved
about that is like a lot of my research
you have to kind of understand and be
very deliberate to actually use it
successfully. Was the single packet
attack we were able to ship it like you
press a button and
>> and it does and you don't even need to
know how it works.
>> Yeah.
>> It will just it will work just as well.
Even with that, I I think I was really
surprised as well how simple that attack
was, you know, like it it just there's
lots of beautiful pieces of that and and
just going back to your the thing you
just discussed there. There's so many uh
places that I want to go there. One, you
know, talking about how, you know, you
you moved outside of your comfort zone
and utilized um Man in the Middle, which
shows a, you know, a more thorough um
understanding of the threat model of
some of these of some of these um
targets. Um, but also I just want to
harp on the for a moment. You said, "Oh,
well, I had two weeks to spare." And I
was like, "When was the last time I like
I want that life, James, where where you
like, h I have two weeks to spare. Might
as well just like jump down this chain
to find an Apache uh CVE." So, I guess
like in in your your flow of research
and you're deciding, you know, what do
you do? You know, what kind of stuff do
you go after? Um it seems like you have
a schedule where you're like, "Okay, in
two weeks I need to be either start
working on this or I need to do this
presentation or whatever."
>> Yeah, pretty much.
>> Yeah. And and so you know, were you at
the end of like a flow of research and
you're like, "Okay, I got two weeks
until I present this. Let me see if I
can pull a CV out of this with, you
know, client sidebased man-in-the-middle
uh desync or how that
>> I I I kind of I give myself a schedule
because if I don't have a schedule,
things are fuzzy and then I get more
stressed. if I know what I'm doing when
and whether I'm on track or not, that
really helps. So, basically my job, a
significant part of my job is to present
at Blackout USA every year.
>> And the deadline for the CFP for
Blackout USA is at the start of April.
>> Uh, and I presented there a lot of times
over the years and I have a fairly good
feeling for whether whether I have
enough good material for a successful
submission to Black Hat.
>> Mhm. or not. So, how I found myself
there was basically it was the middle of
March and
yeah, I think yeah, I think it was the
middle of March and it's like I've
written my CFP. I I'm happy with it. Um,
and there's no other kind of loose ends
that I need to tie up and then there's
just two weeks before the the deadline
and I'm like, right,
>> dang,
>> let's get down to this.
>> That that is freaking awesome. And and I
I actually added another note to our
section here. I want to swing back
around to that because I think um one of
the you know security aside, I think one
of the biggest things that correlates to
happiness in your career and in your
life is having you know control over
your schedule, having a little bit of
freedom, right?
>> Yeah. You know, I I've been amazed that
you've been able to do this for so for
so long. Like you did 10 presentations,
I think at at Black Hat or something
like that. This is your 10th, right?
That was that was number 10 just a few
weeks ago. Yeah.
>> Congratulations. You've been doing this
for a long time.
>> Yeah. And and you've been able to avoid
burnout. You've been able to, you know,
work through it consistently. So, um I
definitely want to swing back around to
that because it seems like you've got a
really good setup there. Um but before
we do that, I we did say that at the
beginning of this episode, we were going
to go ahead and acknowledge the whole
Kaido versus Burp thing. uh and and say,
you know, that um we're not going to
cover this too much on this episode, but
obviously, you know, uh both of us are
are players in the HP proxy wars or
whatever. Um and uh we just wanted to
say at the beginning that what we've
kind of discussed off air was that we're
both really happy that there is um you
know competition in the space and that
we are all working together you know to
kind of push the space forward as far as
getting functional tools for for hackers
to use promoting research um you know
education right with with uh the academy
and everything. Um, so I think there's a
lot of there's some heated aspects to it
all, but I think, you know, from this
side, uh, you know, for for us at least,
I think we're both happy to see, you
know, that competition in the space. Did
you have anything else you wanted to add
to that, James?
>> That's absolutely it. Uh, we've got
we've got a shared objective uh, of
empowering hackers. Uh, and well, yeah,
the software that we use to get there is
different. Uh but a space in which
there's zero competition is not overly
not overly healthy really. So
>> I see competition as a good thing. Uh
we'll see uh we'll see where it takes
us.
>> Yeah, absolutely man. Totally agree. And
and with that, I did want to hop into a
couple questions I had for you about
Burp Suite. Um and you know, these are
these are applicable to HTP proxies in
general. Um obviously some of the
research that a lot of the research
you've done has just been very um
focused pinpoint on HTTP and and you
know HTTP1 HTTP2 all of the HTTPS really
you know um but specifically uh one of
the things that I I kind of wanted to
get your thoughts on is repeater's
implementation of HTTP2
is essentially a downgrade uh right is
like you display to the user a HTTP1
like representation of HTTP2 um which is
a binary uh protocol and uh you know as
I started to understand HTTP2 a little
bit better and I and I largely through
your research ironically um uh you know
I was realizing hey this isn't really
like a an accurate picture of what HTTP2
looks like under the hood right um and
and so I I want to get your thoughts on
um one whether you agree with that uh or
or and and two whether you think that
there's room for improvement in HTTP2
representation to hackers inside of a a
sort of a a repeater replay like
environment um that that promotes a
deeper understanding of the protocol or
gives more flexibility.
>> Absolutely. Sure. So uh when I started
to do research on HP2 which involved
sending
requests with HB2 that could not be
represented using HP1. uh it quickly
became apparent that there's a lot of uh
there's some complexity here. So we
tried a few different things. What we
ended up going with is basically
uh our view is most of the time when
you're looking at a HTTP request, the
protocol isn't isn't super relevant to
the attack that you're doing, right?
you're just like, I want to tamper with
the parameter called blah or edit the
header with this name or whatever. So,
so for for that scenario, which we think
is most of the time, uh that's why we've
got this like HP1 style representation
of a HTB2
request. uh it's just the easiest way of
uh like like it's a comfortable familiar
way of doing your normal work because
most of the time what the protocol is is
not really relevant to you as an end
hacker. Uh but obviously there's
exceptions to that and so the the way we
handle that inside Purpuite is if you
pop out the inspector and go to the
headers uh then what you can see there
is
like a B is is an accurate
representation of what is actually going
to be sent. So if if you do that on a
HB2 request, you can see the pseudo
headers. Uh you can inject duplicate
pseudo headers, you can inject
space in the names,
>> all that kind of stuff. Yeah, it's a bit
hidden to be honest. Uh so you could
easily
>> miss it, but basically using that you
can do a whole lot of crazy crazy stuff
with HB2. uh it's just hidden there in
the inspector for when you want to do
that.
>> If you use it, you you'll find sometimes
uh if you do something like inject a
duplicate pseudo header,
>> uh then you'll lose the main raw view
because it can no longer be represented
faithfully using HTTP1 style
>> syntax.
uh which is yeah we were like well this
is just accurate representation right at
at the end of the day we're we're
building power tools for hackers we
don't want to be lying to people about
what's actually happening
>> under the hood uh we want to be picking
basically like even presenting a HB1
request in a tool it's an abstraction
right because HB is actually a stream of
byes. Uh that's why like pipelining
confuses people so much because
they're reading too much into the
abstraction.
Uh and with HP2 what we found is
basically you there's two different
abstraction layers that people want to
work at. So we surface both of them in
repeater. Uh to be honest, we put a huge
amount of work into building that and
then I haven't actually seen that many
people finding cool HP2 issues where
it's looked like they've been using it.
But I would view it as it was probably
still a good investment for the long
term because there's definitely more of
these cool issues out there with HB2 and
they're just going to surface o over
time. Dude, I I wish the audio listeners
could see the love with which I'm
looking at James right now. Like that
was such a beautifully nuanced answer
that that considers the hacker in so
many ways, right? Like you give us what
we we need most of the time, you know,
thinking at the application level,
right? Um and then you also give us the
tool to go a little bit deeper and tweak
the protocol stuff through inspector.
And is that I mean is that the whole
concept behind inspector like you know I
guess I've seen inspector mostly as a as
like you know I often you know when I
was using burp I would have the you know
decoding sequences or whatever that were
on the right hand side that was really
cool but then there's also this
component of inspector where it allows
you to dive a little bit deeper into the
protocol um you know so is that is that
the kind of concept behind inspector
giving tools to go a little bit deeper
or
>> Yeah that's pretty much it. It's a bit
of a power tool uh for for when you want
to Yeah. for when you want to maybe
decode stuff, encode stuff.
>> Yeah, we're looking at putting other
things in there maybe in the near
future. We'll see how it goes. Yeah.
>> Another example, just a tiny more other
thing on on HB2, right?
>> In HB2, as you well, as you probably
know, uh all the header names are
actually lowerase,
>> right? So for our initial internal build
uh when we represented HP2 uh as a HP1
request, we had lowercase header names
and oh my goodness is it ugly. It's
>> oh my gosh, dude. Yeah,
>> it's really jarring.
Uh so I think that was one of the things
that pushed us really early on is like
we hate lying to the user and about what
case something is because that can
matter. But on the flip side, it's so
ugly that it made us realize really
early we need two systems here.
>> There's a lot of there's a lot of nuance
here for sure because like you said,
most of the time we don't need protocol
level control. We need we need to be
thinking at the application. Yeah. I
mean, it's still application layer,
right? But it's like like you know on
top of the application layer a little
bit.
>> Yeah. And and um I I think that's a
really beautiful and and nuanced
approach. Um and and and and I think
when I wrote this question down, I was
kind of thinking about HTTP2
as like a totally different protocol
than HTTP1 because it is so different in
so many ways, but it's actually still
HTTP, you know, like the the whole
concept is is like, okay, there there's,
you know, there's get, there's post,
there's parameters, right? And these are
all similar.
>> It's supposed to be the same thing from
the application's point of view, even if
that doesn't really hold up in reality,
>> right? So, it's kind of like a Yeah,
it's like a pseudo protocol, you know,
it's like a I mean, it is it's a V2 of
the protocol. Um, very interesting.
Excellent answer there, James. Thank you
so much for that. I think that was
really nuanced. Um the next thing that I
wanted to talk to you about specifically
relating to to Burpswuite and and and
that whole flow is um how how are you as
a researcher using AI, you know, with
Burpsweet or without Burpuite um to sort
of progress your your research? Um and
you mentioned before, you know, this was
before I had AI, so I had to, you know,
raw dog it or whatever uh before. Um how
is that integrating into your workflow
nowadays?
>> Uh in a few different ways. So, uh, some
of them, you know, I'm exploring at the
moment, so I can't really talk about
stuff I'm going to be publishing in the
future. Uh,
>> dang it, James. Give us give us give us
>> I can't help teasing things. Uh, I would
say, uh, is is really useful for
learning and getting up to speed with
topics really, really fast.
uh like I used it to learn about uh
unicoding coding attacks and such like
which was always a blind spot for me
because there's a crazy amount of
complexity there. Uh and I was able to
basically get to a much better level of
understanding really really fast using
it. Uh also in some cases it will just
kind of just drop novel techniques on
you. Uh I experienced that this year
with I'm trying to remember the exact
sequence of events but this wasn't even
with deep research. Uh
I said
I'm trying to remember the details. So
>> I remember you tweeted something out.
You were like AI just dropped something
crazy on me and I'm like oh jeez.
>> Yeah it sh I found two cool things with
it. I can share one of them. Uh it's
it's in my HP1 must die research as like
a random technique right near the end.
Uh if you send if you combine the trace
>> method with the with the max forwards
header it works on twice as many targets
>> dude
>> right it's crazy and I would have never
thought of doing that and if you look
>> in the RFC which is the classic read the
RFC I don't think it mentions combining
those two headers but I think chat GPT
had seen and you know maybe in some
forum post from 20 years ago
people talking about using the trace
method in conjunction with max forwards
to like debug what was happening on a
server and so it just spat this
technique out and I tried it and it
worked and it was like wow thanks
>> that's the craziest thing ever I
remember seeing that I think in your
presentation you know where you were
like it was spinning out these sort of
intermediary headers which is massive
like understanding what's happening
>> oh my gosh at that at that like you know
especially when there's o happening at
like the reverse proxy stage where and
then it's like adding you know assign
JWT or something like that in a specific
header and you're like oh if you know I
just know what that header is or
whatever then you can try to send a
version of it or do some sort of header
smuggling which we'll talk about later.
Um yeah the trace plus max forwards dude
I did not know that was an AI find.
>> Yeah, I shouldn't really get the credit
for that one. That's chat GPT but
>> dang the thing that's crazy. Yeah, if
you use deep research, it it gives you
like 100 ideas and 99 of them are just
so bad.
>> Yeah.
>> Unless you know, you still need the
knowledge because you need to look at
you you can't try out those hundred
ideas and it can't try them out for you
yet. So, you need to find that one.
>> You need to recognize it. So, you still
need the knowledge to get the value out
of it.
I think I think another piece that's
really big on that though and I think
you alluded to this in the you know
Apache man in the middle thing was that
>> it does help validate ideas too you know
like I think more than ever uh now I I
can use AI to just very quickly like all
right spin up this you know
configuration or I was hacking on an SDK
the other day and I was like uh you know
I got to like set up all this stuff for
the SDK and I just handed it to AI and
it just built this beautiful like PC
script that just set up everything in
the SDK and like handed all the objects
off to each other and then got me to my
sink, you know, and uh that is just got
to be, you know, I know that that's big
for bug bounty hunters, but it's even
got to be, you know, massive for
researchers that are constantly having
to deal with the burden of like, let me
set up this whole architecture to get to
test this on ASP and and Django.
>> Absolutely. I mean gosh
>> to be honest that's why I always work
black box because I I can't be bothered
setting stuff up and much test on live
websites.
>> Uh but is redefining uh what's possible
there.
>> Wow, dude. I think James, let me just
pause you there for a sec. So you're
saying you don't do a lot of that setup?
>> No, I basically never set up targets.
>> Oh my god, James
the freak. How are you one of the most
successful security researchers in the
world and don't do any like sandbox
setup?
>> It's too much work. I can't go.
>> That's crazy, dude. That's crazy because
I feel like that's such a pivotal piece.
That is such a different take from so
many of the other researchers that we've
had on this podcast. You know, most of
them are really like, "Hey, dude, put in
the time. you know, get a debugger
hooked up, you know, like get, you know,
and and and I mean, to be fair, I guess
a lot of your stuff is like, you know,
not necessarily finding zero days in
like enterprise software or anything
like that, you know, but but uh you
know, it's more protocol level, you
know, architectural zero days, but still
that's amazing to me that you don't you
just test on websites. I would
definitely say put in the time, but
personally I put in the time where I
want to put in the time and that's not
installing and configuring enterprise
software. Dude, that's amazing, dude.
James, you are living. You are so let's
let's jump into the the conversation we
were going to have before then, which is
like you've been doing this for a long
time. Security is notorious for burnout,
especially, you know, when you're doing
research and you're just kind of banging
your head up against stuff and and
you've um done 10 Black Hat talks now,
you know, very consistently been pushing
out new research on a regular basis. How
do you h how do you structure your life?
How do you live your day-to-day? How do
you avoid the burnout of security
research?
>> This is a good question. So I think
one key thing here uh is autonomy. Uh
you need to make your own decisions and
kind of find what works for you. Uh and
that's like like uh I'm the leader of
the research team at
>> Portswiger and that's how I lead it.
everyone on the team has a lot of
autonomy to decide kind of what they're
researching, what they'll prioritize,
what leads they'll chase down, and what
their day-to-day looks like. Because
>> I don't think research research is a
creative process. Uh
>> it's like trying to
>> Yeah. So I I don't think you can just
kind of grind it out uh by forcing
everyone to to like work in the same way
because I don't think you'll get the
same results doing that. So having that
autonomy and that choice
>> is really important uh for avoiding
burnout. Uh
>> yeah. So, so do do you like just pose to
your researchers like a question like
>> like I is it just do research like you
know what what what is you
>> how do you prompt them? How do you how
do you because everybody else is going
to have you know their own method for
how to do research, right? You know
they're everybody's unique, right? Some
people need more structure, some people
need less structure, you know. Um, and
everybody on on the fre everybody on the
freaking Portswiger research team is
cranking out research, you know. So, so
um I guess I I guess you know all of
that could be from excellent hiring
decisions and surely that's a component,
right? Um but you know what part of the
meta strategy, you know, do you think
helps people
>> I get
>> produce good results?
>> I guess there's a bunch of things. One
things is one of those things is we give
people a lot of time,
>> right?
>> Like we're basically doing research full
time virtually. Like yeah, we spend
maybe we spend some of our time, you
know, like helping improve burpuite and
so on. The majority of our time is spent
on research. Uh that helps a lot. uh the
main thing that I do I don't really try
to say I I don't tell people how to
approach their research or what their
topic should be really uh they would
suggest a topic and I'll just ask some
questions to kind of quickly see
is this promising is this going to go in
the right direction if this goes if this
fails like how much time do we have to
in invest test before we know if this
research is going to work or not. If we
invest loads of time and then the
research fails, do we at least learn
something useful in the process that we
can apply later? Uh it's that kind of
stuff. It's just like like such things
that mostly come from a lot of time
spent researching myself and a lot of
lessons learned along the way. Dude,
yes. Th those are such that's such good
those are such good questions to ask,
you know, and and uh yeah, that's
definitely a part of the reason that
that guides because sometimes you're
like, you know, you get a it's very easy
to get nerd sniped or whatever by like,
you know, some very weird quirky
functionality, but you're like, okay, is
the result of this going to actually be
something impactful? You know, is
>> Yeah, exactly. like different
personalities have different kind of
wrong wrong turns that they'll be prone
to make them to uh to making. Uh
>> yeah.
>> Yeah. And it's about kind of spotting
those recognizing them in yourself.
That's the best place to start.
Recognize them and then just going like
oh wait I'm not going to fall for that
one for the third time.
Right.
>> Well it's about improving. Yeah. Like
you're saying you know it's about you
know knowing yourself as well as a
researcher. I think that's that's that's
pivotal. Um, sort of building on that, I
think earlier in your career as a
researcher, as I was going through like
the freaking mountain of research on
your website, um, you you were focusing
a little bit more on client side stuff
in the beginning and then as you've, it
seems to me a little bit as you've
matured as a researcher, you've been
focusing more on on on server side
stuff. And not not to say that that is,
you know, the, you know, one thing or
the other, right? There's a lot of
mature researchers that focus more on on
client side stuff, but I'm wondering why
you whether that intention or that
decision was intentional or whether that
was something that just sort of
happened.
>> Uh I definitely I I would say I drifted
into it to an extent.
>> Uh I think part of it is, you know,
Gareth Hayes has been on my team for 10
years now and he's really good at client
side stuff. freaking Gareth, man. Oh my
god.
>> He joined shortly after me and we
immediately got this dynamic where it's
like, well, if it's a client side thing,
I can just give it to G and I know it.
So, to be honest, that's probably a core
part of the reason that I've been
looking at server side more. Uh, also as
like
I find this stuff where you've got
multiple components and issues that only
appear in production super valuable. uh
as someone working for Burp Suite, we
have a dashed scanner, right? And we are
competing with SAS scanners that look at
the code. So when I'm finding novel
classes of like desync stuff like that,
that stuff that SAS basically can't
find. So it's it's like extra valuable
for us because because our competitors
in in the SAS space aren't going to be
able to be like, oh, we can find this
stuff better than Burpuite. So, it's an
area where I can deliver more value to
Portfiger more easily, too. Uh, also, I
think over time, I just love the black
box. I love the mystery. It's like why I
don't even like setting things up. Like,
I love these systems like Akami where
it's like you don't even know how many
proxies they've got in a chain. All you
know is it's more than you would
possibly imagine.
>> Oh my god.
>> It's It's like that. Um, I think this is
part of avoiding burnout way, you've got
to be having fun
>> and curious, you know.
>> Yeah.
>> And for me, when you're testing
something like proper black box, it's
like at any time you could be like one
bite away from the server going insane
and have no idea. And it's that like
that mystique that kind of keeps me
hooked and and motivated on on research.
>> Dude, that's so funny, man. you you and
the blackbox thing, man. I Yeah, I see
it now. I see it now. And I think that
that is also something that's really
relevant to buck bounty hunters, right?
You know, a lot of the time we don't
have the luxury of being able to just
spin up a local copy of all this, right?
Um so I think that a lot of a lot of
research stuff, you know, research and
bug bounty are adjacent. And I think um
but not not the same. And I think one of
the things I read somewhere in that
mountain of writeups you have um was you
saying something like security research
a lot of people will say oh you know bug
bounty hunter security researcher same
thing or whatever right I I really do
agree with you that that there is a a
difference here you know bug bounty
hunters they're all out there they're
they're finding zero days they're doing
their thing you know hacking on stuff
but research I think is more of a a
protocol level an architectural level
sort of endeavor in a lot of ways Um uh
and so I mean well I don't want to put
words in your mouth. Do do you is that
how you represented it?
>> Yeah, pretty much I would define a
researcher as someone who is trying to
find novel classes of attack or novel
techniques kind of trying to improve the
state of the art
>> uh rather than applying like existing
knowledge to find bugs.
Uh yeah, I do think a lot of bug bounty
hunters do do bits and bobs of research
here and there, but I think part part of
the issue is
>> as a bug bounty hunter, you don't always
have a good financial incentive to share
just to share your research,
>> right? Yeah. Especially if it's like,
you know,
in this cloud environment thing, right?
If you see a lot of like reoccurring
cloud misconfigurations or something
like that, you know, or or something
that affects um you where things can get
in a misconfigured state and at that,
you know, makes them more vulnerable to
these sort of architectural problems,
then it's really big. And I think the I
think a lot of hunters have done a
really good job of taking your request
modeling thing and just like beating the
[__] out of everything with it,
>> you know?
>> It's great. I love it. That's exactly
what I want to happen.
>> Yeah. Yeah. So that's that's really
awesome. I know the book bounty
community loves you James for that
reason.
>> I've even seen it with tools like with
>> param miner that was the first parameter
discovery tool like the concept I think
it basically didn't exist until I made
that
>> and I just released it and the number of
people that have come up to me and be
like oh I found remote code execution
using this tool. I'm like
>> if I was a bounty hunter I'd be killing
myself if I published that tool instead
of keeping it for myself. Exactly man. I
mean the amount of money that has been
generated from freaking param miner is
insane dude. Uh yeah beautiful but going
back to the blackbox thing. Yeah I think
I think there's some researchers you
know or or some hackers like you like
Fron um there there just a lot of a lot
of they just have a big amount of
intuition and curiosity about how these
systems are are structured. And for me I
think that's that's really difficult.
you know, just sort of talking about
myself as a researcher, I think one of
the reasons I I really like client side
stuff is it's so tangible and there and
I I I can very easily identify exactly
what's happening and and you know, take
these gadgets and train them together,
you know, and chain them together and
like, you know, produce a result. Um
whereas, you know, you're saying the
opposite of that is is what's inspiring
to you where you're, you know, you're
banging your head against something, you
can't figure out why it's doing the
thing, and that is what fuels you.
>> Yes. is the challenge. It's the chaos. I
love it. Like my basically all of my
favorite bugs I found by accident,
right? Like my research, if I had to
summarize my approach to research in
three words, it's like make accidents
happen.
>> Yeah.
>> Right. Like that's it.
>> Yeah. two two two thoughts, you know,
from what you've said that sort of chain
together with that is like um I think
one of the quotes from uh one of your I
I'll read it here. Um let me see if I
can find it. Um this is from one of your
many presentations. I didn't grab the
exact spot, but it says, "When building
automation, make it really easy to ask
questions of your data set. When you do
this, you'll start asking a lot of
questions, even the stupid ones, and
then the results from the stupid ones
will surprise you, which gives you
interesting research topics. And when I
heard that, I was like, "Dang, that's
amazing." Right? And that's kind of what
you're talking about here, where it's
like, you know, you ask questions of
your data set, you you you you and even
stupid ones, right? And then when the
results surprise you, that's where you
should, you know, dive in a little bit
deeper.
>> Absolutely. Yeah. Like that's where the
intersection of of like automation and
research.
So like automation and human human power
works works so works so well when kind
of that's what's driving my approach to
to AI stuff too. Like personally, I kind
of I see like a bunch of people have
this really strong emotional reaction to
AI that kind of then dictates how they
engage with it. And personally, like
like I do too. I love it for its power
and I hate it for the stress and anxiety
that it's causing people. But
ultimately, my emotions are not relevant
to it. It's there. It exists. And why
not just make the most of it?
>> That's my view on it. And and it's a
step up in automation, but you can
compare it with automated scanning. Like
like I saw someone uh on your channel
mention a while ago, uh if we'd kept
Burp's scanner to ourselves, we'd never
published it and then we ran it on all
the bug bounty targets, we'd be number
one of the hacker one leaderboard,
right? by far
>> not expo.
>> He's really good at XSS and so on. Um,
so in a so my advice with AI is like
don't don't panic about this like it's
just a new kind of automization a new
kind of automation but also don't ignore
it
>> either because it's a seriously powerful
tool and like classic automation I think
it works better with human in the loop
too.
Uh, I've always like if you look at all
of my research, it's about combining
human testing with automation to achieve
results that are much better than what
either can get on their own. Uh, and
that's why I work at Portzviger and not
you don't like there's loads of dashed
vendors that that make scanners. Uh, but
Porzviger is the is the one that has a
tool that really combines human humans
and scanning effectively. And I don't
think AI changes that. Uh
>> you've got a lot of companies, you've
got a lot of companies that
basically aren't in the pos they they're
like building AI enhanced scanning, but
they're not in a position to offer human
in the loop because they don't have
access to a tool like like Burpuite or
Kaido to build on. So they're forced to
build
>> a scanner that's fully standalone,
right? And then they they're going to
market that as a pentest really heavily
and they're going to tell you over and
over this is better than a pentest. It's
going to put all the pentesters out of
business because they're not able to
build a human in the loop thing, right?
>> They probably know human in in the loop
is better. Like that that's my view on
on that whole topic. Basically,
>> I agree. I mean it it makes sense,
right? Like why would we not have a
human in the loop? just give the AI, you
know, let the AI do their thing and then
let the human be like, "No, no, no,
you're screwing that up. Hold on." You
know, go this way. You know, like it and
you're absolutely right.
>> Strengths, isn't it? Yeah.
>> Yeah. You know, as a as a you know, like
you said with with HTTP proxies with
Burp or Kaido, you know, we have a
platform on which researchers are, you
know, using looking at the HTB protocol.
They're familiar with all this. they're
they're analyzing applications and then
we have an opportunity to integrate AI
into that to enhance it, right? Uh
versus just doing, you know, an AI
scanner or whatever. It it is that is
definitely the most powerful approach,
you know, to all of this. Uh and I did
want to grab another quote out of here.
I'd like to cherrypick your your your
quotes a little bit, James. It says,
"There's an old cliche that automation
is about finding lowhanging fruit, but
this is dangerous because when used
correctly, it gives us a platform to
stand on to reach high hanging fruit.
And that applies perfectly to what
you're saying, right? AI, Burp, Suite,
Kaido, whatever. These are platforms on
which we elevate researchers and allow
them to function at a higher level to
reach those things that are not, you
know, easily accessible. Right.
>> Exactly. Yeah.
There's the strengths of AI and skilled
human testers are just not the same. So,
you've you've got to combine them if you
want to get the best result possible. Uh
obviously like I think AI powered
scanning is super cool. I think AI
combined with Gast is great and you know
we're working on releasing that. Of
course we are uh because it's more
scalable and so on. But if you want to
find those top quality bugs
>> using both is the is the easiest way to
get there.
>> Absolutely. Um let me go ahead and jump
back into a little bit the the rearch
research meta. We kind of I feel so bad
for like my team that has to go through
it and chapter stamp all of this stuff
in the video cuz like I'll follow these
little rabbit holes down. But anyway,
team, we're going back to the research
stuff. So, put that in the in the in the
chapter notes. Um, so you know, one of
the things that I think is important for
bug bounty hunters to understand about
research. uh and I think there is a
pipeline there right of bug bounty
hunters sort of moving into security
research and a lot of the skill set you
know is is intercompatible and it's a
good way to fund your security research
in the end so there's lots of
compatibilities there um but I think one
of the notes you have here is
understanding your true objective with
research as a researcher um can you talk
a little bit about how one might find
that true objective and why it's
important to know
Absolutely. Yeah. Basically, do research
is is a really vague kind of concept and
and my question would be what is your
actual specific goal because depending
on your goal uh you will be wanting to
approach it in very different ways. Uh
so for example, I I would say like early
on in my research, part of my goal was
basically just to make a name for
myself. Uh to be honest,
>> uh but and I used to think that the and
then my job well then it was my job
deliver a presentation at Blackat,
right? And you can check that box, but
it might be a bad presentation, right?
So that's actually not a good outcome.
It's probably better not to deliver a
presentation than to deliver a bad one.
But then what makes a a good
presentation? So for example,
uh a lot of people go to presentations
because they want to they want to be
inspired, right? So think about what the
end goal is. Like do you want to inspire
people to take the techniques in your
presentation and apply them for
themselves? Uh, that's a pretty cool
goal. Like I would say seeing people
using a tool you've made or using a
technique that you've shared is really
rewarding. Uh, or maybe you want them to
build on your techniques. For me, that
feels even better when someone takes my
research and does their own research on
top of it. That's creating this like
feedback loop, which is super super
cool. Uh but those two objectives kind
of can be intention quite a lot. Uh
>> for example yeah
>> that that makes sense and and I think
one of the ways you promote that as well
is you very clearly at the end of your
presentations and in some of the other
people in the re Ports research team do
this as well where you say hey these are
future research topics
>> you know that I was like that I think
are really cool. You serve it up on a
golden platter to the community like A
lot of people still don't pursue it. But
>> yeah, like like and it's and right, you
know, I'm glad you say that here on the
podcast because there I I would like I
would like to challenge the community a
little bit, especially if you think
you're if you're doing okay, like a lot
a lot of our listeners are full-time bug
bounty hunters, right? Um and and so I
would say you know if if you do see
yourself progressing into research at
some point uh as a as a either as your
progression in a buck bounty hunter and
you know using um your research to fund
bounty or maybe you just want to move in
that in that way. There are very few
people taking up James on his on his you
know offer in the presentation. Hey, do
do research here. Do research here. And
those are very high value leads, right?
Like these this this is this is
something James is saying, yeah, this is
what you should go after. Like, you
know, as a professional that's done this
for for 10 years, 10 black hat
presentations, take these and go. Um, I
think it's a really worthwhile
investment. And we've seen, especially
in the um uh you know, HTP desync or in
smuggling ROM, you know, how many people
have done this, built upon it, and found
really, really cool stuff.
>> Yeah. We've seen some awesome some
awesome stuff happening in the field.
And I think what I would also say to
bounty hunters is this. I can't tell you
if you publish your cool technique or
your cool innovation or your cool tool
that that that you know people are going
to shower money on you directly for
doing that. But
writing things up to publish them will
make you have new ideas. it's that when
you try and frame something and explain
it to make it accessible to a broader
audience, uh you will have your own
breakthroughs as a result of the kind of
the cleaner thinking and articulating it
better. And then also when you share it,
other people will build on it and share
back which can be super valuable.
>> Like in the last year's research, you
know that we made over $350,000
in bounty.
>> Insane
them. Yeah,
>> that was 100% because of the
collaborations that I I did. And the
thing that made the collaborations
possible was the fact that I've
published research
>> on those topics in the past. So, I think
publishing research is a is a super
valuable
is a you are sacrificing value in the
short term, but you're gaining it in the
long term.
>> Yeah. And and you know, when you release
these things to the community, you're
also putting yourself in jeopardy for um
research collisions, right? Uh but that
that's a risk you're taking because
>> Yeah, I hate research.
>> My worst nightmare.
>> I I say the word research collisions and
James eyes go like, uh
but but you do you put yourself at risk
for that, right? and and um that's a
part of the the the game, you know, just
like dupes are a part of the game in
Book Bounty. Research collision will
happen in in security research. Um so I
I I thank you on behalf of the community
for still pointing us in in various
directions after these presentations. I
think that's extremely valuable.
>> I have one tip actually how to avoid
research collisions. I learned this very
painfully cuz we lost a black hat USA
presentation
>> on SAML due to a research collision with
GitHub.
>> Oh, really? Oh, with GitHub. Oh, [__]
>> Yeah, I have some rude words about that,
but uh
>> the pain. I can see the pain in your
eyes, dude. James, I just want to pause
and say I love how passionate you are
about all this, right? like I you you
were almost tearing up a little bit in
the Black Hop presentation when you
talked about using the slash cocon,
you know, to exploit the zero CL dsyncs
and and I was like, you could see the
passion when you're like for years I've
known about this quirk and then I
finally used it, you know. Um, thank you
for the for your passion for all that.
But yeah, I'm sorry. What's the what's
the tip on on avoiding?
>> Uh, the tip, right? The tip is basically
if you see sometimes you'll see someone
publish and you post
on on on a technique and you'll be like
that is super cool. It's really valuable
and I've got some ideas for how to take
this further. Okay, it's like an amazing
research lead.
And my tip is it is a good research lead
if you're going to publish to
investigate it immediately and publish
what you found straight away. But if
you're aiming at a conference,
you know, you've got to submit to the
CFP months and months before and if it
looks that promising, there's a
significant risk that someone else has
seen the same thing and is also working
on it. They're going to snipe it.
>> I I wish I thought of that when we read
we read this awesome research on a SAML
technique and we were like this is
great. We can build on this and we built
on it at the same time as GitHub and
Positive Technologies as well. So they
published theirs when we were about to
submit it to Black Hat. So we published
ours. We like wrote it up really fast.
Publish it like 2 days later cuz they
left out a proof of concept and we were
like nah you guys have proof of concept.
Uh, and then like 3 days later, Positive
Technologies had to publish this as
well.
>> Oh my gosh, dude. It's like freaking
research race here.
>> It's horrendous. So, my advice is if you
see someone something like that, do it
fast or do what I usually do kind of by
accident, which is say that sounds cool
and then forget about it for 2 years and
then pick it up and do it because if
it's been a couple of years,
>> probably no one else is looking at it.
>> Yeah. set yourself a calendar reminder
for two years and and be like swinging
back around to that SAML thing. Um, man,
I I did see that post, the SAML post. I
did not get to that in my prep for this
episode. So, I'm going to have to circle
back around to that and and um yeah, re
refresh my brain. Sam is like
>> SAML is whack, dude. And there's this
guy
>> that research setting up SAML
environments,
>> right? Exactly. Like and and uh and
yeah, man, there's just so much weird
stuff in XML. um yeah and and as well.
So yeah, it it's crazy. Um let's let's
go ahead and swing back around to uh you
know, you you've done a lot of write
writeups on
the metag game of of researching. Um and
you have some tips uh about how to do
research here. Um, hunt forgotten
wisdom, uh, forgotten knowledge, collect
diversity, no idea is too stupid,
abandon comfort. And I kind of want to
just jump through each one of these
because I really think that these are
high value principles and just kind of
get your thoughts on each one of them
and then ask a couple questions. So tell
us a little bit about unforgotten
knowledge, why that really helps um,
sort of fuel your research.
>> Absolutely. So uh, basically
people have short memories. people, you
know, like social media drive stuff that
was published in like the last what 72
hours.
>> Yeah.
>> And then and then stuff just kind of
disappears and everyone forgets about
it. Uh so
what that means is there's this like
hyperfocused lens of attention on the
latest thing and
people kind of think that you know in
general a post published a week ago is
just going to be more valuable than
something published
6 years ago. Well it it's often not
true. Uh
obviously the best example of this that
I have is request smuggling. It was
literally explained really nicely in a
white paper in 2004.
>> No way.
>> And when I read the white paper, I copy
pasted an exact like payload
from that PDF and it exploited
everything on Akami.
>> No.
>> And I literally picked that p that that
payload cuz they gave you like 12
attacks. I just picked the easiest
looking one. The only one I could
understand at that point.
>> Oh my gosh.
It was ridiculous.
>> That's crazy.
>> And you still see that there's still
there's super old
>> there's really old valuable stuff, but
people kind of pe
and there's there's this like hidden
knowledge like there's all these people
that understand
like they've read old stuff and they
remember it but they're not going to
reshare it because you know it's someone
else's
tech technique and they're not going to
talk about it. So the knowledge is kind
of there buried in the industry in weird
niches and granite isn't right but
uh it's not surfaced and if you want to
get that knowledge you either need to
find like an oldtime hacker and
interrogate them or you need to read old
stuff.
>> Wow. Yeah, that's awesome, man. And I do
think it would be really cool to have I
don't know how they do this, maybe with
AI or something like that, but like have
some Twitter bot or something like that
that just cherrypicks old research from
from like you know whatever
whatever sources and then just retweets
it at random, you know, intervals, you
know, just says boom, what about this
one? What about this one? Does this
trigger anything with you, you know, for
you? I think that would be a really cool
It's all like link rot is making it
harder and harder, but obviously there's
there's archive.org.
>> Yeah.
>> For that.
>> Thank god for archive.org. We we all
need to go support archive.org, man. Cuz
if that if that site I know they're
they're constantly like, "Give us a
dollar." I'm like, "Here, like take
money because if that ever goes away,
we're screwed." You know, we lose so
much if that ever goes away. We do
preserve Portzer preserves all the uh do
we uh we preserve all the nominations
for all the top 10.
>> Yeah.
>> Uh so we do have copies of those but
everything else is toast and a lot of
people
>> don't a lot of good stuff doesn't get
doesn't get nominated as well.
>> Yeah, man. The nomination list each year
too.
>> It is it's horrific.
>> I have to read all of those.
>> It's like oh my god. Yeah, dude. I can't
imagine for you cuz I complain I
complain every year whenever you guys
release the top 10 I'm like oh my god
like this like the prep for this episode
is like like a full week of reading and
researching right like 40 hours uh for
where normally I put like you know maybe
four hours into four or five hours into
prepping an episode you know this is
like 10x you know really um and and man
I can't imagine how much of a thing that
must be for you and the and the team
that's you know auditing each one of
those you know going through each one
reading it.
>> Jeez, man.
>> That is That is But what a fun thing.
You know, that is your job, dude. Your
job is to go there and read security
research.
>> Yeah, it's a good job.
>> I freaking love that for you, man.
That's amazing. I I did want to ask on
this specific um you know, bullet point,
hunt forgotten knowledge. One of the
things that I advocate a lot in the bug
bounty world for mostly for beginner and
intermediate hackers is, you know,
really trying to spend time with your
hands on the stuff, you know, like
really get in the HTTP request, tweak
stuff, figure out what's happening, you
know, really spend time experimenting.
Um, as a researcher, I'm as a high
performing researcher, I I'm wondering
what your perceived ratio of like
knowledge gathering or reading versus
experimentation is.
Uh, that's a good question. I would say
this has changed a lot over the years
for me. Uh
when I started out for I would say maybe
I don't know 5 years I basically read
everything I could get my hands on. I
was just always reading. Uh
I would just read everything even if it
was not even super super related to like
web security. I'd like read all of
Project Zero's blog posts even though I
didn't really understand a lot of that
stuff. Right. Yeah.
>> Uh
>> that makes two of us.
>> Yeah. But over time kind of as I'm
uh as I've got more experience and I'm
more like if I'm building on my own
research uh the need to read other
people's stuff kind of drops a bit. But
>> I enjoy I still spend like every day I
look at what's been published and I read
the stuff. So I still do it daily
because people still publish stuff that
I find super super valuable and it gives
me really nice ideas. Uh but I would say
the these days I definitely spent a lot
more time experimenting
>> with things. Yeah,
>> it's good to know. Good to know. Um,
next item on the list here is collect
diversity. Um, can you talk a little bit
about that principle from a research
researcher perspective?
>> Yeah, it's it's often basically when
you're doing research, you're trying to
find things that other people haven't
thought of uh or tried. Maybe they have
thought of them, but they haven't tried
them. But there's got to be a reason for
that. And often it comes down to making
connections between quite different
fields or between different perspectives
like that browser powered browser the
brow the pause based man in the middle
client side desync
>> that is like a tongue twister man you
can't it's like there's like 15
modifiers on that desync it's like
client side man in the middle like oh my
gosh
>> yeah like that's combining like a server
side desync attack with client side
exploitation
with a
with a man-in-the-middle kind of concept
based on something that from ages ago.
So,
it's that kind of being able to to make
those links will often surface really
valuable stuff. Uh it will often let you
take something that looks like it has
very little impact and turn it into
something significant. M
>> uh yeah, I I'm a firm believer that
combining blackbox and white box testing
is really valuable even though I don't
follow my own advice
in this regard. Uh but I'm definitely
going to be looking at some point I'm
going to crack and actually actually
start doing that. Uh kind of every Yeah,
I
>> you got to outsource that [__] James.
You know, like you've got you've got
you've got a you've got a whole port
team. just be like, "Hire somebody who's
like the setup guy." And he just I think
that's called a system what a system
admin.
>> Who would apply for that job?
>> Yeah, dude. I mean, that's pretty much
what a CIS admin job is, right? Like
like Yeah. I don't know, man. That does
sound like the worst thing ever, though.
Like set up all of these enterprise
software, set up this whole stack.
>> Oh my god. You couldn't pay a hacker
enough to do that, I don't think.
>> No. I I actually I have a great example.
Uh yeah,
>> there's someone whose Twitter handle is
something like Z Hero
>> and they've been doing really really
nice cash poisoning research by looking
at the source code like in depth of of
of various frameworks. They've been
doing really really
>> nice work and it's it's like server side
exploitation that that's only possible
by combining these kind of two different
approaches.
>> Yeah. going going after the all I think
we've covered a lot of those on the pod
like going after a lot of the JS
frameworks and stuff like that going for
the cash poisoning very very good stuff
there yeah I did want to ask relating to
collect diversity obviously you know
before the onset of AI there was a lot
of like oh I really I think it was a lot
more it was a lot easier for us to have
to to how do I say this to justify
spending a lot of time getting a bunch
of different perspectives Right? Because
what like you mentioned before now with
AI we can say hey give me the the you
know tldr of this whole concept you know
or it does this specific thing exist
right and and it'll you know do its
magic and and try to pull something out
of thin air um with with AI how has
collect diversity changed and do you
think it is still as relevant to do um
versus asking pointed questions to the
AI?
I think it's kind of just a a means to
an end of achieving the same thing. Uh,
one thing to watch out for with deep
researchers, it basically does loads of
Googling and a lot of the time the good
stuff it doesn't show up on Google
because Google surfaces, Google really
likes things that were posted in the
last year and then it's like they just
disappear after that. Uh, which is
ludicrous
>> and it's not very helpful for research
at all. So if what you're doing is a
load of Google searches under the hood,
that's not it's I mean it's better than
nothing, but it's not ideal. Whereas
what AI has that's really valuable is
it's like that trace thing where it's
like it probably read
read a Stack Overflow post from 20 years
ago or something like that. Yeah,
>> Stack Overflow, you know, I found some
amazing techniques by reading and and
and on Stack Overflow and it's like a
developer asking a question and they if
you have the security knowledge and you
read the question, you're like, "Oh my
goodness, you just discovered the
detecting technique." Exactly. And they
have no idea.
>> Oh my god.
>> They have no idea. And none of the
replies have any idea either.
>> Yeah. I think that's so funny. Also,
when doing like white white box stuff,
I'm just scrolling through the code and
sometimes there'll be a comment in there
and you're and you read it as a security
and you're like, "Yep, they're they they
knew what was happening here." You know,
if only they had the hacker's lens, you
know, they're like, "Some for some
reason this feels off." And I'm like,
um, yeah, security definitely Stack
Overflow is is a a gold a gold mine,
man. It really is. Um, next thing you
had no idea is too stupid, man. This is
this is massive in security, right? Uh
you you kind of shout out in your write
up, never underestimate the security
bystander effect cuz it's freaking
everywhere. Um and and I think Oh, just
hit my mic there, but um you know, kind
of goes back to what you were saying
before is, you know, you're serving up
these research uh ideas at the end of
your presentation and not a lot of
people are are taking up uh you know, on
them. So diving a little bit deeper,
getting that extra, you know, validation
even on things that you're like, "Oh,
that that that couldn't work, that
couldn't work is is super important." Is
that kind of the concept behind this
one?
>> Yeah, definitely. I think the number one
people think that the number one mistake
that that you make is picking the wrong
research topic.
>> Yeah.
>> And I think that's a complete
misconception. I think the number one
mistake is not trying is not attempting
the topic, telling yourself it's not
going to work and then just not having
that shot.
>> Uh
>> yeah,
>> you always you always learn something.
If it's cheap to try it out, you should
try it out. And if it's really expensive
to try it out, try and figure out a way
of doing it that's not expensive and
then do it anyway.
>> That's really good, man. I I think one
of your ncon talks no con hunting
evasive vms uh one of the quotes there
is that will never work unless and then
dot dot dot right and you kind of build
the presentation a little bit around
that um I think that's such a good
powerful question for researchers to ask
themselves is like what what you know
first our brains sort of write this
concept off and what edge cases could I
really be missing here that would make
this really simple seeming thing act
actually happen it's really
Um I did the last uh item here that I I
had from your you know how to be a web
security researcher talk was abandon
comfort. Um and I I watched the recent
interview you did with uh Tiberious and
you said in the beginning you weren't
too hopeful about HTTP request smuggling
as a as a whole concept and then but you
ended up going deeper into that. Is this
sort of an example of you sort of
abandoning comfort or is is this you
know I guess the the like what made you
a little bit unsure about that topic in
the first place?
>> So when I did uh my webc poisoning
research
>> I developed this research philosophy of
what you should research is what you're
afraid of. That's a great sign of a
really valuable research topic.
uh that works super well for webcache
poisoning. And so after the research and
and and I explained that in the in the
intro to the presentation. So then after
delivering that presentation when I was
thinking of my next research topic, I
was like, you know what, what am I most
scared of? And the thing I was the most
scared of was request smuggling. Cuz I
watched this presentation from Regillero
where he it made absolutely no sense.
And he said, "You definitely won't get
paid from anyone because it's too
dangerous."
>> Oh my gosh.
>> And of the first time that I read that,
I I was like, "Okay, I'm just going to
stay away from this." And then when I
was thinking, "What am I scared of?" I
was like, "It has to be that. That's
what I'm most scared of."
>> Wow, dude. That's amazing. It, you know,
and and I think it I think that's a
really good balance, though, right?
Because I think on one hand, you were
really scared of that. you were scared
of the impact it would have on on you
know the targets your approach these
blackbox you know rand testing random
sites that sort of thing um obviously
it's a pretty technically depthful
vulnerability but I think it also aligns
a bit with your skills prior to the the
whole um the whole
HP request smuggling thing right like
you had already done some research on
cache poisoning and also host header
related attacks right so you know that
sort of
>> uh reverse proxy architecture um
attacking that whole flow, right, which
we mostly only see in production. Goes
back to that whole DAS thing you were
talking about earlier. Um
and so there's there's been a lot of
pieces. I I wanted to sort of challenge
you a little bit on this on this point
um as far as your research methodology
goes because it seems like reverse
reverse proxy architecture has become a
like a a really
um sort of a safe spot for you as from
from like a a research perspective,
right? We've seen that with your host
header based attacks, you know, back way
back in like, I don't know, 2017 or
something like that. Um, we've seen that
with cache poisoning. We've seen that
with HTTP request smuggling. Um, do you
how do you know when
is the time to abandon that that comfort
zone of reverse proxy based architecture
uh and move to something else versus
continuing to push it if if it still
gives, you know? Do do you understand
what I'm asking there?
>> Yeah. Yeah, def definitely. This is an
excellent question. Uh, so you're right.
Like researching request smuggling or
cash poisoning is not scary for me at
all. Right. It's like the one topic
where I have the most confidence that my
research there will find some crazy
stuff. M
>> uh and so and when I delivered uh
browser powered desync attacks where I
introduced client side desync attacks so
that presentation
>> crazy crazy by the way I just I so good
continue
>> that that's probably my f my like
personal favorite piece of research
because of uh how technical it got. I'm
sorry. I'm going to interject to here as
well. I I would have thought that would
have never worked, right? That's a
perfect example of that will never work
because I don't have any control. I'm
sending a cross-sight, you know, uh
freaking you know, browser controlled.
I'm working within the constraints of
what the browser allows me to do with a
fetch request and somehow you are able
to induce DC. Unbelievable. James, I'm
sorry. Continue.
>> It was crazy. And a whole bunch of that
stuff was exploiting client side like
browser connection reuse behavior and I
had no idea how any of that worked and
looking at Chrome source code didn't
help at all.
>> Yeah. Right.
>> Uh uh so
I like I love doing that piece of
research. It was super satisfying for me
as a researcher. But then when I
presented it, it didn't land as well as
some of my previous talks. And I think
there was a couple of issues. one was uh
you needed a lot of prior knowledge in
order for it to make any sense. So the
the kind of the audience that it was
valuable to or accessible to was
smaller, but also like in terms of the
bounties, it wasn't that great. So it
didn't get people hyped for it in the
same level. And after that, I was like,
you know what, I'm kind of getting bored
of researching request smuggling and or
no, it's like I'm still enjoying it, but
I don't want to just become this person
just the request smuggling guy.
>> Yeah.
>> Right. Like
>> any more than I already am. So that's
why the year after I did race conditions
and then the year after that I did
timing attacks and the single packet
attack and so on. But then most
recently, why did I go back to request
smuggling? Well, basically,
uh, I had Alice. So, I was like, I've
got no sleep. I'm barely functional. I
need something
>> Yeah.
>> that is I need something that's I'm
going to find relatively easy. So that
was what pushed me to to be like
>> like when I started it my goal I already
knew that the title was going to be the
desync end game. I was like
>> there's I I know there's stuff that
needs to be wrapped up. There's there's
still people missing loads of findings.
Uh
we need to kind of we need to wrap this
up. That was my goal with that piece of
research.
>> Dude,
unbelievable. I really love that because
it also combines, you know, research
methodology with knowing yourself,
knowing where you are in life, knowing
what your capabilities are. You know,
you push yourself outside of your
comfort zone and you return to your
comfort zone when you need to. And I
think that's such a beautiful example of
how to win the long game
>> because so much of all of these all of
these things are, you know, that people
run into burnout with bug bounty, people
run into burnout with, you know, all
sorts of things. But you need to know
what you're you need to know your own
limits. Know what you're capable of. Not
constantly be push push push push grind
grind grind. When it's time for you to
focus on family stuff, then you fall
back to what's easier for you and what's
functional, but you still stay in the
game, you know, like Yeah. I think
that's something I really struggle with
because I feel like for a long time I I
really wanted to just constantly be, you
know, at the top of the live hacking
event leaderboard and constantly be
like, you know, pushing out S tier
content on critical thinking and like
just constantly be just crushing it. But
then I realized like there's times in
life where, you know, you've got other
things going on. You know, you've got
new kids in the in the in the house,
right? you know, you've got um
priorities and you're not going to be
able to to function at at your at your
top level. So, you make the adjustments
and you still produce something
excellent. I love that, James. That's
really great. Thanks for sharing that.
>> Yeah. Yeah. Yeah. It's People also keep
asking me on the same topic like when
are you going to do more research on
HB2? Like when are you going to do some
like HB2 endto-end attacks,
right? And
it's it's this it's this the problem is
right I can hack HP1 and compromise like
20 million websites 40 million websites
right relatively easily.
>> Yeah.
>> Or I can research HTTP2 and put in way
more effort and probably
compromise
like 10 websites. Well, maybe I'll like
pop one CDN if it goes really really
well, right? But it will still be one
target and
>> it'll be patched and then you it won't
be as you know. So,
>> it's this challenge of like what's my
objective? Do I want to deliver
something that you can then use
yourselves or do I want to deliver
something that you look at and go wow
that's some really hot stuff but I
didn't understand half of it. I can't
build anything on it.
>> Excellent
>> either.
>> So, for me it doesn't make sense to
research. I can't justify researching
HB2 until HB1 is like pretty dead and
that is why I so want to die.
>> Dead. It's dead now post this
presentation. James has killed it. Um
that's awesome, man. Uh good good [__]
I think I think the last place I want to
go with this whole research thing. Um
well, okay, actually two things. I got
to get gota gota pause for a second
here. Um, I did want to ask you, you
know, as as a person that is running the
research team, you know, at at
Portswiger, uh, if you have any advice
for for me, because I, um, you know,
we're spinning up the critical research
lab, uh, under critical thinking. And
all of this is just kind of like me
taking this podcast and trying to do
what I think is cool, you know, and one
of the things I think is cool is
Portfiger research, you know, and and
and um and I think it'd be really cool
to have more people have the opportunity
to be financially incentivized to do
research. And obviously, we're not at a
point in with the podcast where um we
can hire full-time researchers. You
know, we just don't have that that
budget. But I do want to like the
concept behind the research lab is to to
you know grab people from the community
that are doing quality research. Give
them additional distribution by covering
it on the podcast and hosting it on the
podcast website. Highlight the
researcher. Celebrate the researcher and
then provide some you know token of
appreciation you know as far as like a
stipend or something like that goes. um
you know to say thank you for
contributing this research you know to
the community and um you know so we
we've got the team together I'm setting
the stage for all this so you can
understand the situation um we've got
the team you know together we've we've
got some cool pieces but it's kind of
scattered and it's not something that uh
you know we've been really diving super
deep into or asking for a lot of uh time
investment on. Um I guess I was
wondering if you have any advice for
that for that structure of research lab
uh or how how you think we should move
forward with with that like how can I
help that researcher facilitate what
they are are researching themselves.
>> Uh good question. So
research is tricky because yeah it
doesn't it doesn't make make money the
same way as like exploitation focused
>> stuff.
does uh and if you don't have buckets of
time to throw at things then landing you
know like landing things like conference
presentations at top tick conferences is
quite hard. Uh
I wouldn't one piece of advice I'd have
is most researchers that I have spoken
to
have a excessively high bar for what
they think is worth publishing.
>> Right.
My view is just publish it. Publish
everything. Every tiny little cool
thing, publish it. And please publish it
in like a blog post or like not just in
a post on X where it's like lost to
history after 24 hours. Like just just
get it written down somewhere and over
time that that will accumulate and
become really valuable.
Dude,
>> that's such a good answer and that's
exactly what I was trying to tell the
research team, you know, and and and
we've just now sort of got a an
environment set up where we can really
make like really quick GitHub, you know,
markdown blog posts and just shoot it
up, right? And I I'm even, you know, as
far as like the stipens go for research,
um really incentivizing
small, quick, dirty, here's a quick, you
know, sweet little trick that I figured
out, you know, sort of post because I
think those are so valuable and those
really help close the gap for a lot of
exploits and a lot of um you know, even
chunks of research. Um, so that is
definitely the hope for the critical
research lab is is like, you know, let's
let's create a platform where we can be
putting out, you know, I really I think
Gareth does a really good job of this,
you know, it's just like I I've seen
some of his posts, you know, on on his
on his website and it's like two
paragraphs, isn't this cool? The end,
you know, and I just I think I want to
try to push the community in that
direction as well. That's really
>> Yeah, that's it. That's where everything
goes. I hate writing like 6,000word
white papers. I I know how many people
read that end to end. It's not not very
many
>> uh small small valuable things. Other
other people will look at it and then
>> they'll like like they'll like like it
and then like use it for their own
technique and then site you for it and
cool things will happen. It's worth it.
>> Beautiful. if anybody has um you know we
our vision for the the critical research
lab is is expanding a little bit here
and um we're gonna accept essentially
submissions from the community. If you
have a cool piece of research that you
want to have uh you know covered on the
podcast on on the on the crit um
research lab website then feel free to
reach out to us on the discord um and
we'll definitely take those submissions
and we will soon be bubble sizing you
know what the stipen amounts for that
are and that sort of thing as well to
give a little bit a little token of
appreciation back to the community. Um
but definitely I want to see a bunch of
little small here's a cool quirk use it
you know sort of post. Yeah, it's super
cool to see more people paying for
research. It's so hard to get paid to do
research.
>> Uh there's so few opportunities. Uh so
>> yeah, I hope more bug hunters
>> work
>> to do that. Thanks, man. Appreciate
that. Um last question on research. Who
are some up and cominging researchers
that you respect their work?
>> Good question. So I'm going to answer
this with two people. uh both of whom
have been researching request smuggling
cuz obviously that's the topic uh that
I'm the most focused on. Hang on, I
write their names down over where? Okay,
here we go. I'm not very good with
names. Like I recognize handles but not
>> dude. It's so hard, man. It's so hard in
this security world.
>> So there have been, you know, but hang
off. First, I have to caveat this
because there's so many people doing
awesome research that they then publish
in some blog that doesn't get discovered
or amplified as much as it deserves by
the community. Like that's why the top
10 exists. It's to try and surface this
stuff, but stuff still gets missed out.
So,
>> I'm missing out a million people, but
this is two people I've seen. Uh, one is
Thomas Stacy, uh, whose Twitter handle
is toxile. He did some super cool
research on using he found the single
packet attack which was basically
developed to find timing attacks and
race conditions. He found it actually
also helps find desync attacks and
request tunneling. Uh which is super
cool. Obviously there's clearly some
kind of race condition involved in
there. Uh I love this stuff where it's
like you only even half understand how
it works. Uh, and I believe he's working
on some new research which is sounds
quite promising although I haven't
managed to get him to give me the full
details of it just yet.
>> Uh, yeah. And the other guy is uh, Yep.
[__] Uh, and he does some super cool
request smuggling research on exploiting
chunk extensions,
which is this is one of those things
I've heard people saying, are you
exploiting chunk extensions or for ages,
but no one was successfully doing it.
And he's just come out there and uh like
basically popped a CDN using it uh
insane. I had a collaboration with him
briefly on a target and I spent days on
this thing and it was it was absolutely
mental and it didn't work but I still
had a great time with it.
>> Dude, it's awesome.
>> That that was such a great write up on
the chunk extensions like and and I love
what he says you know in that post he's
like you know nobody sends this but all
of them support it right like that's
such a good area for research is if the
HTTP server or you know try to more
broadly apply this any anything
processing data if there's you know
a a very uncommonly used feature that is
still implemented, you know, in that it
it's very likely
>> everyone implements it. So, what you're
looking for is look at an RFC and find
stuff where you're like, I didn't know
that feature existed. That is gold right
there.
>> And that's the beauty of being a little
bit more of an experienced researcher as
well, you know, is like, you know, or or
at least an experienced hacker, right?
You know, you're looking through all
this stuff. you you kind of know mostly
the most of the ins and outs of of you
know the system, how the web works, that
sort of thing. And then you're like,
"Oh, wait. I didn't know that that
exists." Well, probably most other
people didn't know that exists either,
and probably nobody's using it. And
probably that's where you should double
click, right? And and try to get a
little bit deeper. Um, I did want to get
your your take on this uh quote from uh
Yep. Cops Wake I guess is his handle.
Um, right up. He po he um sort of quotes
this law of robust computing uh Postel's
law. It says be conservative in what you
send and liberal in what you accept. Uh
>> it's a disaster,
>> dude. I was That's exactly what I
thought you would say. I was like, this
is like uh this is where James lives,
right? Isn't that exactly where you
live? Yeah, I nearly when I was
designing my slides for HB1 must die
this year, I nearly titled a slide
something like Postals [__] up, but then
I was like,
>> "This is a bit mean."
And I'm probably going to upset too many
people by saying this, so I didn't do
it. But
>> that's that's brilliant, man. Yeah. I I
think when I when I see that quote, it
makes me so happy. I'm like, "Yes,
that's what we want."
Beautiful. Um, so we spent the most of
the time already on this podcast talking
about just research methodology, you
know, understanding how how to do
research. Um, now let's get into some of
the research itself. I did want to Oh
jeez. I said earlier on the podcast it
was 2017. The host header attack stuff
that you did was 2013, dude. Oh my gosh.
Um, that's amazing. So I I guess I I was
going back through some of this stuff
and I think one of in my personal
experience of your research, one of the
first things that I you know where you
came on my radar was when you were doing
a lot of these HTTP um host header based
attacks where you were using these as
SSRFs, you know, to sort of hit
different backend servers.
>> Yes. Cracking the lens. That was it. Um,
I thought that was an amazing technique
and I know that you uh it seemed to me
like that was a little bit of um the
first time that the community at large
sort of understood the dangers of
reverse proxy based attacks. Was that
sort of the same for you as well?
>> Yeah, definitely. Basically, at the
time, everyone preferred to pretend that
reverse proxies didn't exist because it
was like, oh, cash poisoning, this weird
alien thing. Like, no one understood
anything in that regard.
Uh, and it was, yeah, everyone was just
scared of it, basically.
>> Yeah, dude. I think it's a I think it's
a really cool attack type. And as I was
going through, I um I I pulled one of
the payloads out and I just put it in my
notes here from your 2013 talk. Um, it
it was hostite.comattacker.com.
And I just love those that at syntax
with the username and the password is
just the gift that keeps on giving, man.
It's really really nice. And I think the
a lot of um parsers out there will you
know see that semicolon or I'm sorry the
colon and think okay this is the
beginning of the port segment but really
and and you would kind of think about
parsing it that way but then as soon as
you see the at sign you're like okay
wait go back you know this is this is
actually the username and password you
know portion of the URL. So, I just
wanted to pull that out and and readress
it for the listeners. Um because I think
that is some really that is a really
cool technique that you that you brought
to light there.
>> Thanks. Yeah, it was good fun. That
research on is on doing password reset
poisoning with
>> with host header attacks is probably is
is the first major piece of research
that I ever did. Uh, and it it was
actually quite eye opening for a super
depressing uh reason, which is so prior
to this research, I sort of looked down
on people that published at conferences
because I was like, the stuff's not that
good. They're just promoting themselves.
Like, they should be spending that time
doing research, right?
>> I didn't have that much respect for
them. And then I published that research
and someone working at a company that
I'm not going to name because I'm nice
uh basically copy pasted that post like
rephrased it a teeny tiny bit and posted
it on their site and didn't link to
their didn't link to my blog and now
their website
>> this is a big company they have way
better page rank than my site so they
ranked higher on Google like the next
day and Then for a period of maybe like
8 years, basically everyone that talks
about password reset poisoning cites
their post.
>> No. On the topic,
>> dude.
>> And it was only when I made the host
header attacks academy topic uh that we
finally got got actually decent decent
ranking again for this technique. So
basically my advice is if you're going
to do some research, promote it as much
as you can and if anyone tells you not
to do that, say stuff you I'm going to
promote it anyway.
>> Exactly. You know, the more eyes that
get on it, the better. And uh and it's
better for the security community in
general. And well, I mean, obviously,
you know, we're here the podcast is
essentially doing that, right? Helping
helping people promote research and
helping the research get disseminated to
the community.
Absolutely. Like we had people getting
annoyed this year for publishing hp1
must die.com
and if you read it they're mad at like
like the curl the curl guy.
>> Yeah.
>> Post an angry tweet and they're annoyed
because we're marketing the research.
But the thing is if you look at their
post they're not understanding it
because they don't understand the
context of the previous research on the
topic. And the reason they don't
understand the previous research on the
topic is because we didn't market it, so
they didn't read it. The only reason
that they're able to criticize us.
>> Yeah.
>> Is because they've actually seen this
research for the first time. So to my
mind, well, at least this time around
they saw the research.
>> Yeah. That's a good lesson learned there
for the researchers. definitely push it,
distribute it, get it out to various
sources because
>> yeah, basically you will get flack for
it, but just ignore it.
>> Yeah, that that's good. Hey, take it
from James right here. We we we heard it
here on the critical thinking podcast.
There's your uh there's your certificate
of approval to go and and uh register
your domain name for your new uh
vulnerability type. Um, did did you have
I I know I'm just kind of throwing this
question uh out of the blue, so totally,
you know, no, I don't have anything else
on this is a perfectly valid answer, but
I was wondering if you had any any
thoughts on, you know, additional
research in the host header realm. I
know that you did utilize it in HTP 1.1
this year, um, you know, with the HV
sort of fingerprinting thing. Do do you
have any other leads or things you want
to sort of shout out to the community on
that front?
Uh,
I think if you told me to do cash
poisoning research right now, uh, I
would look at using header smuggling to
smuggle the host header.
>> Uh, I do cash poisoning that way
because,
>> you know, with the with the desync,
we're going to talk about this later,
but with a desync endgame, basically
header smuggling doesn't always result
in a in a desync. So then you've got to
look at alternatives. So it used to be
if you could smuggle a header, just
cause a desync, job done.
>> But now I think other approaches are are
valuable. And the host header like it's
it's used everywhere. It's it's it's
it's like the the
it's the source that goes into like the
most syncs
>> anywhere,
>> right? Like there was a exploit for
WordPress where you like do a password
reset with a payload in the host header
and get code execution or something
along those lines like it ends up every
it ends up absolutely everywhere.
>> Wow. Yeah. And and I think a lot of the
difficulty too with the reverse proxy
architecture is is obviously there's
some you know foot guns with the whole
host header thing and and vhosting and
and that sort of thing. But I think you
get a you lose a little bit of
flexibility you know when this reverse
proxy is like very specifically looking
for a specific host header. If you're if
you're dealing with direct access to the
HTTP server, right, and there's no
intermediary, then there's also a lot of
weird things you can do with the with
the host header um that that will end up
at very weird places. Uh absolutely. Um
let's sort of building on that, I think
we should talk about the the HVH thing,
which we'll we'll get to in a second. So
let's let's dive into HTTP 1.1 must die
the desync end game the talk that you
gave at black hat this year I was there
in the audience clapping screaming
whistling um you know so excellent
excellent work man um can you give us a
little bit of a recap well first let's
set the stage talk to us
>> for you know 30 seconds a minute on what
HTB request modeling is whole concept
and then we'll we'll dive into um
specifically the research that you did
this year on like 0.cl CL um uh
exploitation.
>> Absolutely. So, HTTP1 uh as you see it
represented in a tool with like a
isolated request and response is
basically a lie. Like it's an
abstraction underneath the hood. you've
got a stream of bytes and multiple HP
requests are sent over a single stream
and they're just kind of whacked one
after the other directly as a sequence
of bytes. And this is a problem because
uh HP1 is a plain text protocol and as
an attacker there's like maybe five
different ways of specifying the length
of a message which means servers can get
confused about where each message starts
and stops. So that means when you've got
a reverse proxy, uh what reverse proxies
generally do is they take requests from
loads of different users and they funnel
them over a small shared pool of
connections to the back end.
So, if you can confuse, if you can get
the front end and the back end to
disagree about where each request stops
and starts, basically you can append
stuff to the start of other people's
messages and generally cause everything
to go horrifically wrong. Uh for
example, the flagship technique
uh is that HP1 has no built-in way of
matching requests to responses. Which
means if you send a request that
triggers two responses,
the front end thinks it loses track of
which response goes to who and it sends
random responses to all the users of the
website, which is absolute carnage and a
very beautiful site every time.
>> Yeah, dude. Uh frick. What a beautiful
attack. And and how crazy is it to think
about just from like a data flow
perspective
that when you're thinking about this
reverse proxy architecture, you know,
your request is right next to, you know,
somebody else's request on that on that
in that TCP stream, you know, between
the between the the reverse proxy and
the backend server, you know, and it's
like that data is right there.
That's it is is it's is there and it's
not well understood. Like when I
originally did the request smuggling
research, one of the people that I
reported a vulnerability to responded by
saying that's impossible
like like then how did I give you a
proof of concept like yeah we recently
published a tool called HTTP hacker uh
like a burpuite extension which actually
shows the underlying stream. So if you
want to kind of get to grips with this,
uh that's quite useful because it will
help you kind of understand what is
happening under the hood.
>> Yeah, I was looking into that a little
bit uh beforehand and I was like, "Yeah,
this is good." Cuz I think that there's
definitely, you know, like you said, a
lot of us are using the sort of
abstracted HTTP
like almost pseudo HTTP layer that that
we're using to just kind of hack the
applications, right? Um, so getting that
lower level access where we're actually
thinking about it as a protocol built on
top of TCP. Yeah. I think is really
>> helpful. Stream like that's the core
concept is HP1 is a stream. Um,
>> yeah.
>> Um, okay. So that's the general, you
know, concepts behind uh HTTP desync
request modeling that sort of thing.
Talk to us a little bit about uh HTTP
1.1 must die. uh what kind of research
came out of that that talk this year?
>> Absolutely. So, I decided to research
request muggling because I was like, I
can still see people finding these
issues and I haven't had much sleep, so
I'll pick something easy. And uh I
quickly realized that although kind of
offtheshelf tools like HP request
smuggler at the time weren't finding
very much on like decently hardened bug
bounty targets. This was just because
loads of web application firewalls were
doing things like blocking using reaxes
to block things with transfer and coding
headers and such like so and they were
also fingerprinting the detection probes
that
>> HP request smuggler was sending. So I
thought okay what we need is a different
approach like a completely different
approach to finding these
vulnerabilities. Uh and I took a cool
tech uh technique pedd by Daniel
Thatcher uh in a presentation I can't
remember the name of called HP header
smuggling something like that
>> practical HP header smuggling
>> that's the one
>> uh and I adapted it like built a more
powerful version which uses more headers
for fingerprinting and so on and
basically what it does is it detects the
ability to hide a header from the front
end or backend server which is the kind
of underlying primitive
of maybe like 80% of request smuggling
attacks and it can do that reliably.
That's and that I think is when I was
sitting in your talk this this year I
was thinking you know and I'll be real
with you James like I'm not a huge um
you know request smuggling exploitation
guy obviously I'm using Kaido so you
know there's not a lot I could do there
with that but um you know it's just not
a big part of my my methodology and I
totally respect the hackers at every
live hacking event you know that that
show up with a request crazy request
mongling bug and pop these crazy crits
um but it's not something that's super
duper on my radar And as I was listening
to your talk, I was thinking, you know,
wow, um, so much of request smuggling is
hinges on this whole concept of header
smuggling. And the the thing that you,
you know, showed with this is extremely
applicable to things that are not
request smuggling as well. The this
whole header smuggling concept and there
because there's so much um, you know,
data that is being stored in headers and
sort of abstracted away uh, in modern
day architectures. So um I love I just
wanted to highlight for the for the
listener like this is very valuable
beyond request smuggling as well just
understanding how this specifically
works uh so that you can smuggle you
know headers that have authentication
based values um you know all sorts of
stuff into these environments. Okay. So
that was my little my little thing there
that can you talk a little bit more
about how you did that sort of um that
tool to to delimmit uh whether requests
can or headers can be smuggled or not?
>> Absolutely. So it just sends a few
probes. Uh it basically says
I like to think of research in terms of
asking questions. So I ask a question to
myself and then I write a tool that asks
the question to the target.
So what it does is it says it asks the
question if I use a given technique to
hide a header
when sending a request to a specific
target. Do I see a unique response that
I cannot achieve
uh simply by sending that header without
hiding it or by hiding like a different
unrelated header? Uh and
by doing that basically it shows okay by
hiding this header with this technique
you've hit a unique code path and then
it uses a massive range of techniques
and it uses a massive range of detection
headers too because for example some
sites will give you a different response
depending on what the host header value
is but some of them basically ignore it
completely. Uh so it's good to use a
range of different headers. Uh but it's
it's just for fingerprinting. That's the
point is like the host header isn't
being used for an attack. It's just
being used as a kind of a gadget to
understand what the target server is
doing
>> because uh you know a lot of stuff is
and there are situations where the host
header is not relied upon very rare
though you know um and so I think this
is a really good way that you
demonstrated this. you know, essentially
what you're doing is trying to smuggle
the host header most of the time, right?
You're like adding a space, you know,
you know, adding these characters to it,
that sort of thing. Um, and then
detecting how the various servers along
the chain respond. Is that an accurate
part of the picture?
>> That's it. I I guess the key thing to
understand like why the host header
might not work is
I consistently make this mistake where
basically I underestimate how complex
the target is. like however many proxies
you think the target has, there's always
one or two more, right?
>> Wow.
>> And any and there's special cases for
everything, right? So if you smuggle the
content length header, oh, they've
probably got a special case for that. So
or if you smuggle the host header
actually,
like one of those servers will be
parsing the host header in a slightly
different way because they want to get
that data earlier to work out which
upstream back end that they're going to
route it to or something like that,
right? So
>> what the overall concept is you're kind
you're kind of trying to dial it back as
much as possible to the absolute
foundation and then approach it from as
many angles as possible to get this data
about can I hide a header or not.
>> Yeah. And I think in your presentation
you represent it as hidden visible or
visible hidden right hv or vh.
>> Yeah. That's how I classify it. like is
it the front end that sees this header
or is it the back end?
>> Now this this is an abstraction. There's
probably 20 20 proxies in practice. But
>> yeah, that's what I was going to say.
It's like hidden hidden hidden hidden
hidden hidden visible, you know, like
you know,
>> right? Like when you write zero CL, you
know, it's it's a lie. It's like CL H2
zero CL.
>> Right. Right. Right.
>> You just got to go what matters, right?
And what matters is is it the server in
front or the server behind that sees
this header because that affects how you
can exploit it.
>> Yeah, dude. I frick I love your
presentations because it it you know I'm
learning about this very technical
vulnerability but I'm also just help
it's helping me visualize and understand
these architectures so much better and
think about these from a threat model
perspective like okay front end hidden
back end visible there's the mismatch
right what can I what can I do here and
and I think um I was I messaged you
recently because I was working on um a a
product um and uh like one of the core
principles of this software is like okay
there are certain headers that cannot be
you specified by the client right and
they they get cut out at the at the web
you know at the intermediary and they
get resupplied because they contain
authentication information right and I
was like this is and it was right after
I saw your talk and I was like oh man
this is exactly where I need to apply
this
you know, hidden invisible thing because
if I can get the front end to not
perceive this as the thing they need to
strip out and then you know and that's
where the the software is that I'm
attacking and then get the back end you
know however many backends there are out
back there because there's a ton of
different you know um softwares that
were running on the back side of this
this software to perceive it then boom
I've just got an off bypass right so
>> absolutely it's it's super valuable uh
if you're interested in that area uh
check out my research on timing attacks
cuz the basically the single most
valuable thing I found with that is a
way to spot that you can use
>> a reverse proxy to access
internal systems and that's another way
of avoiding the same thing because it's
like the intended front end will be
stripping the or the orth header but if
you go in via a different front end you
can dodge that header stripping and then
smuggle headers to that back end.
>> Yeah. a different front end.
>> Yeah,
>> header based authentication is uh like
without proper secret keys is really
quite scary stuff.
>> Yeah, dude. Wow. Lots of cool applicable
stuff there. Okay, so HV um VH there's
that component. Uh talk to us a little
bit more about the other pieces in HP
1.1 must die specifically ZCL and expect
would be great.
>> Absolutely. Uh so when I ran into a HV
scenario where transfer encoding was
blocked I was like well how do I exploit
this cuz if I smuggle a content length
the front end doesn't see the content
length so it doesn't for the body so it
never gets to the back end and the back
end is waiting for this body and the
whole thing times out and the attack
fails and that you can see well if it
worked that will be called a zero CL
desync and this is a situation that I'd
previously kind of seen and been like,
"Oh, that's impossible. That's that's
never going to work." Uh, but while
researching timing attacks, I realized
that actually sometimes servers respond
without waiting for the body and that
breaks this deadlock. It makes the
attack viable. So, basically, if you
find this, you need to find a way to
make this backend server respond early.
on the target that I found this on. This
was a VDP and it wasn't even a VDP that
lets you like disclose reports to them.
But it was like super super low valuable
in that respect, but it was what showed
me
this this scenario. And the target was
running III. And I found that on IIS, if
you hit a file name that corresponds to
a Windows device driver, uh the server,
it gives you a response. It says the
response code is 200, but the body says
44 not found and it responds early
without waiting for the body to arrive,
which breaks the deadlock and means you
can exploit it via a double dyn
and and I went back and I you know
listened to it again and I was like
[__] Okay, cuz I don't that it does get
very very complicated there. But
essentially what what you're doing there
is using this exit this early exit sort
of code path, right, with connection to
make it not wait for the remaining bytes
that it's perceiving from the content
length, right? Yeah.
>> And then
>> and then that those extra bytes like
that's where you lose me. How does the
desync solve that? The double dynink
solve that. Okay, so basically zero CL
by itself, it lets you chop bytes off
the start of the next request
>> because it's perceiving it as the
>> body of the previous request
>> of the previous request because
specified by the content length which
was not perceived by the front end
server,
>> right?
>> Okay.
>> So, it lets you chop data off and
obviously chopping data off by itself
>> isn't great for an exploit because you
need to add your exploit to the request.
So
what you this is where the double decent
comes in, right? So you you use the fact
that you can chop bytes off to send uh
to chop data off the next request
uh such that you like you chop the
content length off the next request and
that way the next request isn't causes a
zero it causes a CL zero desync and you
can inject the body basically something
like that. James, what the freak, dude?
How do you I mean, it's got to be I
think you mentioned this in your talk,
but it's got to be really hard to get
those requests to align properly, right?
>> Well, uh the way I did it for the whole
research was yeah, the servers are
injecting headers, which means the
offsets are wrong and you have to brute
force the offsets and the offsets change
when you give the attack to someone else
like a triager to replicate.
>> Oh no. Uh but I found a better way where
by injecting in the headers uh the
offset you don't need to worry about the
offsets. So if you look at all my proof
of concepts they've got like weird
offsets and stuff but that's because it
was only later that I discovered there
was a better much much easier way of
doing it. Uh so make sure you do it that
way and don't just copy the approach I
took in the proof of concepts.
>> Gotcha. Wow, that's crazy, dude. I I
just And you know, while we're on the on
the zero CL, you know, topic, I just
wanted to say again like I just I gained
so much respect for you as a researcher
when in that moment when you said and
then I found SL,
you know, and and it and I it was always
there and I loved it and it I think you
said it was an emotional moment for me.
I think is what you said in the
presentation. It it absolutely was
because basically I used to be a pen
tester and every time I did a directory
brute force on a target running I
this/con would show up and I'd be like
>> but I couldn't do anything with it by
itself it's harmless
>> and now you have caused lots of harm
with it James well done
>> yeah over a decade later I was like it
was literally the first thing that I
tried
>> dude that's amazing um last topic on on
uh HTTP 1.1 must die expect header. That
That was crazy [__] dude. What What the
heck is going on with the expect header?
>> This one took me This one took me by
surprise. Uh, I started using the expect
header because I was trying to to
detect, what I wanted to do was detect
that you could do a zero CL desync with
automation without having to
successfully guess a early response
gadget
>> because, you know, that's like work I'd
rather do manually because I might be
finding novel gadgets and stuff, right?
And so I figured out you could use
expect to do this. But then when I
started using expect, weird things
started happening.
And then I got this message from uh from
some other bounty hunters like like
Sweetly Medusa and Bisop and they were
they'd also noticed that expect had made
weird things happen and then I realized
that I actually published a payload
using expect a few years ago in request
smuggler but for some reason either I
just didn't bother testing it out myself
and I just published it or when I did
test it for some reason it didn't find
anything. Um, but actually the expect
header is bonkers. It's it's this thing
of it's a thing. It's in the RFC.
Everyone supports it. Uh, it adds a ton
of complexity. If you try and implement
it yourself in a proxy, you'll discover
how horrific it is.
>> Yeah. What what does it even do?
>> What it does is it breaks sending a
request into a two-part process in order
to save bandwidth.
So the so as a client you're meant to go
I want to send a really big request and
the server goes oh that request is too
big don't send it and then you stop
before sending the body.
>> Okay
>> or the or the server goes yeah that's
fine and then you send the body.
So it's absolutely bonkers cuz it like
gets right into the heart of the HV1
state machine and the content length
parsing and all of that stuff. Uh, and
as you can see from the number of
vulnerabilities found using it, it
basically breaks everything. And no, no
browsers support this. Curl is the only
tool that supports this.
>> Freaking Curl, our enemy, you know, that
that uh that says, you know, ah, this
this is overhype. That's hilarious that
Curl is the one that supports it. Um,
>> indeed.
>> Yeah. I I love that you just kind of in
your presentation you're like, "Yeah,
just kind of throwing spectator in there
and sometimes it'll do stuff like I
thought that was great."
>> Yeah, it came out of nowhere. This is a
great area for further research.
>> Yeah.
>> Uh I didn't put much effort into doing
more research with it cuz just sending
it by itself, we just got absolutely
flooded with findings.
>> That's amazing, dude. What a what a
crazy thing. Um,
all right. That HTB 1.1 should be dead.
We killed it.
>> It should be We need to kill it. That's
the message. It's not dead, but the
community working together, we could
kill it.
>> It re It really does need to die. And it
doesn't need to die on the front end. It
needs to die in the back end between the
reverse proxy and the, you know, origin
server. Correct.
>> Yes. Right.
>> Yeah. Um,
very cool. So I guess did you have
anything else you wanted to to comment
on or that you thought the community
might might find um interesting from
that talk? Obviously you know they
should go watch the talk themselves but
as far as like TLDDRs go. Yeah, I think
one one other thing that might be useful
that I didn't really talk about in the
talk because there was time uh is it
surfaced this uh it surfaced this
interesting kind of difference in
approaches when I work with these other
bounty hunters which is that I
discovered the zero CL basic concept in
a like a very kind of methodological
like theoretical manner like I was like
okay I I can see what's happening front
end doesn't see the header. Back end
sees the header. How can I exploit this?
I'll do XY Z. Right? So then I started
working with these bounty hunters,
right? On the expect thing, but I'm not
telling them about ZCL desyncs, right?
Because I I don't really know these guys
super well at this point. The trust
isn't fully established. I don't want it
to leak
>> or my blackeyed tour goes in the bin
like the SL one. Um, but then I could
see the expect header was causing zero
CLD6 and they were like, "We can't
exploit this for any more than a DOS."
And I'm kind of telling them like,
"Let's look at those ones later. Dig a
little deeper."
>> Right. Right. Like like like I can help
you with these ones in a little bit.
Right. And then eventually they find the
one on I think it was GitLab and the
server
happens to when it instead of giving
like a normal bad request response, it
actually tells you why it was a bad
request. So it will say something like
invalid header name and then print out
like a fragment of the body or a
fragment of the status line.
So because they saw that they were able
to figure out the same attack concept
but from a completely different
different angle. Basically if you throw
crazy stuff basically servers will
actually give you the answer. You don't
always have to approach stuff from this
theoretical understanding. Like that's
one way of finding things. It's a
valuable way but you can also find it
the opposite way and you'll find
different things like both approaches
are super super valuable.
That was something that this research
like really taught me
>> that that definitely is
yeah
a very Jameslike approach to research
here you know like as well you know like
I I know that you like I was thinking
through this whole likecon thing and
apparently you thought of it and sprayed
it out there um you know and got the AIS
service to respond with it um but yeah I
think trying to rely on on getting those
hitting a lot of targets with the ideas
and seeing which ones will actually give
you more information back. Um I I I
think that does I mean there's
definitely pros and cons to that though
as I'm thinking through it. I'm like you
do have to parse through a lot of stuff.
You know I I know you've got your your
data set of like you know 30,000 servers
or whatever you normally throw stuff at.
Um but but I think you do need to sort
of go through each one of those results
very granularly versus like setting up a
specific environment. But you do get
such vast amount of uh you know you
could never set up all of the things
that they that these production servers
have in place.
>> No no like all those CDN issues you
can't set up those CDNs like those these
things are happening in inside their own
systems.
>> Yeah.
>> Uh
>> wow.
>> And they're like writing posts saying
like I don't understand what's happening
inside their systems and it's like but
I'm still hacking them.
>> Yeah.
So, so both approaches like having the
theoretical knowledge is really
valuable, but don't don't not try
something just because it's
theoretically impossible.
>> Basically, you've got to be open
open-minded to like you never fully
understand everything and you never
will. It's it's it's too complex. You
kind of got to be humble really.
>> Yeah, absolutely. So moving moving to
like some more general request smuggling
based questions. You know you say HP 1.1
it's got to die and we should be using
HTP2 for all you know um intermediary to
backend communications and I'm wondering
is HTTP2 really the solution? Um because
there's different layers of abstraction
to HTTP request smuggling. you know,
maybe the first layer is is, you know,
getting a header smuggling and then a
disagreeing in, you know, where the
where the HTTP request ends or not
because of the, you know, smuggling of
the the header. Um but sort of at the
end of the day the bigger principle is a
mismatch in expectations between
multiple servers in the chain and and I
think that my theory is that that will
always exist no matter what protocol
we're using because no um you HTTP
servers are going to completely agree on
on how HTTP2 even should be implemented.
So do do you anticipate that we'll see,
you know, a good amount of of
request smugglingesque vulnerabilities
in the HTTP2 realm as well once we
switch to that on the back end.
So I think HB2
uh
ver virtually cures request smuggling.
And that's defining that's defining
request smuggling
as I can send a request that influences
the next request or a request from
somebody else. That that's defining as
something that breaks request isolation.
Right?
It basically fixes that because there it
removes all the ambiguity about where a
request starts and stops um
>> because of length like
>> it's like TCP like
>> I don't know what the last time that
that like a like a massive like someone
was able to compromise 20 million
websites because
>> a TCP library got confused about the
length of a TCP packet.
>> Yeah.
>> I mean, don't get me wrong, I'm sure
that you that used to happen
back in the day, but basically it it's
like, you know, the length of the
message is from like the fourth bite to
the eighth bite.
>> That's it. It's just those bites. How do
you send two two lengths? It's not
possible to send two lengths. How do you
send a an ambiguous message when it's
just these bytes to these bytes? Like,
you know, maybe you can do an integer
overflow or something if you're super
lucky. Uh, but you're talking about like
basically memory corruption kind of bugs
virtually. Like they're going to be
rarer. They're going to get spotted and
patched out and as soon as stuff's
reasonably hardened,
it's going to become really rare.
>> Uh, but as your point, it's not going to
fix things like header smuggling. So
ambiguous requests are still going to be
useful for exploits. Maybe you can do
header smuggling, maybe you can do cash
poisoning. Those attack classes I think
are here to stay and will survive
widespread use of H of upstream HP2.
And also HP2 is super complex and it's
got crazy things like HPAC. So the
compression used in HP2 is stateful
depending on the previous messages sent
on the connection which is like why this
is they've gone too far in the name of
performance
>> uh when doing that and the end and the
end result is some absolutely crazy bugs
like there's a CV I don't think the
actual full details are public but CV
2023 32731
uh you can call something almost like a
desync using HPAC. Um,
>> oh my gosh, dude.
>> So, that's kind of not pretty. Uh, so I
definitely believe there are super cool
bugs in HP2.
>> Oh, yeah. Yeah, absolutely.
>> And I look forward to the time when I
can actually justify doing a good amount
of research on it.
>> Yeah. I was I was um you know I asked
you this question because I was I was at
this Google live hacking event recently
and um Ben Kalis was there uh the guy
that built HTTP Garden and has been
doing a bunch of like request smuggling
you know stuff and I I love this guy.
This guy is hilarious to me because like
the first time I met him, I was like,
"Oh, this guy is interesting because
he's at this Google live hacking event
hacking something with print f in
netcat, you know, like and I'm like,
you're not going to use, you know, like
burp or kaido or whatever." And he's
like, "Got to got to control the got to
control the bites." And I'm like, "Okay,
all right, dude." Um, so I was talking
to him and he was and I I asked him like
some off question about uh the you know
sort of similar concept header header
smuggling and he's like starts telling
me about HTTP2 and he's like do you mind
if I like tell you a little bit about
HTTP2 actually no he's he actually he
let me know in advance he's like all
right I'm going to take you down the
rabbit hole you sure you want to do this
right now and I was like it was close to
the end of the event sure and so the man
whips out a presentation on HTTP2 that
he's like I'm going to give this talk at
work next week and then he goes through
the whole thing explaining to me like
all of the weird [__] in HTP2 like you
know there's like this this um I'm going
to have them on the pod so I'm not even
going to try to explain it all now but
it is it is extremely nuanced and very
weird how like
>> you know this this cache of like headers
exists and like it's super weird
>> um so I imagine there will be a good
amount of ambiguity you know in in
various implementations across HTP2 as
well
>> yes yeah I think ambiguity will be
there. Uh crazy implementation bugs will
be there. Uh what the basically there's
lots of cool stuff for hackers there
still. I it's just not it's just not
like the absolute gold mine of
compromise of millions of websites with
very little effort that is HTTP 1.1. I I
guess also I you know this um I forget
the technical term for this but you know
HTTP2 does the the you know message
length thing right where it's got these
different cells and it says okay you
know this is the length of the message
blahy blahy blah you see this a lot with
binary protocols yeah um
>> and I mean just kind of thinking through
it obviously I think this is a
>> one of the things request modeling
brought to light is that the
delimiterbased system is broken and
really you do you do need to move to
this like sort of message length based
thing. Would you say that that's true in
general? Cuz so many I've seen so many
things pop up where protocols are are
being exploited taking the principles of
request smuggling and bringing into SQL
into like all of these other things.
>> Yeah, the delimiter like textbased
protocols delimiters definitely not
good. Uh as that as that SQL research
that you you mentioned, I believe it was
called SQL isn't dead. Was it Defcon
last?
>> Yeah, it was like 20 24 Defcon.
>> Yeah. So, it's super cool research and
that that's like for me that that's like
the future of request smuggling
basically that kind of thing.
>> Uh it's going to be that level of effort
and it's going to be that kind of like
relatively constrained impact compared
to what we're doing
>> right now. But it's like yeah, hell no.
You you can still achieve high impact.
Well, because if I remember correctly, I
think that that was integer based
overflows, right? Affecting the message
length, right? And then, you know, if
you have some and then, you know, the
message gets kind of cut off and then
the next part is perceived.
>> Yeah, it's chaos. It's chaos.
>> With our research was though, like how
much more difficult it was to get to an
exploit,
>> right? Like with request with request
modeling with H1, you get your desync
and then it's just like easy rolling. M
>> whereas the amount of effort like there
were some targets where he was able to
cause like the equivalent of a dating
but still couldn't achieve much impact
just because of quirks about how the
server was
>> Yeah. and how the binary protocol
>> Yeah. the binary protocol is built out
you know there's a lot it becomes a lot
more like binary exploitation where
you've got to like spray and stuff like
that. It was
>> it was it was a beautiful talk but it
man it gets a lot more complex
>> research.
>> Yeah. Yeah. Um, I guess you already, you
know, you you kind of shouted out HPAC.
Is there anything else that that comes
to mind as far as HTTP2 goes of like
that's sketchy, that's weird, you know,
what and and I don't want to make you
give away your, you know, areas of
research that you're going to go after
next time you, you know, deep dive
HTTP2, but is there anything else that
kind of comes to mind there? Uh there
was one thing I saw was uh I had a post
a while ago on HP2 connection con
contamination where
>> web browsers will if I remember
correctly send requests intended for
different
websites over a single connection
because they think the front-end server
can support all those different websites
>> which is like a vhosting thing. Yeah,
exactly. So, there's Yeah, there's
definitely some kind of broken and scary
stuff in that area. Basically,
>> that's super whack. I wonder if they do
it off of like TLS certificate or
something like that.
>> Yeah, exactly. It's basically TLS. So,
if the site presents TLS searchs for two
sites and you try to connect to both
sites, they'll both get sent to that
website and I think it will like skip.
It won't even bother doing a DNS lookup
for the second website. It doesn't care
where that website is cuz it knows it
can talk to it here. Again, it's this
like they care so much about performance
that they're putting in things that uh
from a security perspective just sound
absolutely insane.
>> Oh my gosh. Yeah, man. I do I we might
have to cut this or whatever, but I I
think it that is super interesting
because you could like I'm thinking like
uh like how can you get it routed to
your site versus the the other site if
you're in like a vhosting environment?
And I was thinking there's a lot of
ambiguity about the dot at the end of a
domain name,
>> right? You know, like if you everything
is like, you know, www.google.com
dot really, you know, and so there's if
you could register
>> there's chaos.
>> Oh my gosh, dude. I'm sorry. Yeah,
that's that is crazy. That's a very good
shout out. Um, okay,
Marathon podcast episode. I appreciate
it. I do have one one last little
section I wanted to hit which is um I
would like to understand more about HTTP
pipelining um and and where that's
helpful and you did just release an or
like an article on uh HTTP pipelining
and I saw it uh this morning somehow I
missed it when I was prepping for this
episode. I I was sitting in the hot tub
this morning reading through our doc and
I was like oh [__] look at this. This is
exactly what I was going to ask. Um, but
can you give us maybe a little bit of
like a TLDDR on this on this article and
help us understand, you know, what kind
of scenarios HTP pipelining can actually
be be helpful to result in request
smuggling or other types of
vulnerabilities.
>> Absolutely. Uh, this is a little bit
tricky because it's a ridiculously
nuanced topic.
>> So, sorry, sorry, James, to put you on
the spot there.
As we've already established,
HP1.1
reuses connection by just putting the
requests back to back on a single
string, right?
>> Uh and that's called keep alive or
connection reuse. And one kind of thing
that's sort of a feature, sort of
accidental sometimes not accidental
sometimes is what this means is you can
send like three requests in one go or
two requests in one go back to back
without waiting for the replies, right?
And generally as you just interpret the
replies in the order that that they come
back and it will work and that's called
pipelining. Okay? So it's not usually a
deliberate feature. It's more like just
because we use sockets and like
underlying operating system socket
libraries just buffer things. So the
application layer might not even know
that you're pipelining or the server
might not know that you're pipelining.
Um,
but what that means, so when you're
doing request smuggling, you're of
you're often sending two requests in one
go, right? You're kind of trying to do
that deliberately. And if you do that,
if you take like Burp Repeater and put
two requests back to back and send them
to a server that's like fast, like send
them to a static file on an EngineX
server, you will see two responses come
back in the single repeater tab and it
looks like, oh my goodness, I've
completely broken the server. I must
have found request smuggling. But it's
actually that's how HTTP works. It
doesn't actually indicate a
vulnerability.
Right. So I guess what I would say is
most of the like that behavior is really
common. It's on engine X on static files
by default. So most of the time that you
see two responses in one, I wouldn't say
there's any evidence that there's a
vulnerability there, right? M
>> um
and if you want to find request
smuggling basically and have it
guaranteed, make sure you're sending
your requests over separate connections
because if a request over one connection
is influencing one over a separate
connection that proves completely this
is like proper request mling.
The problem is that that's not the end
of the story
>> which is that
>> not that simple. Some front ends only
reuse the connection to the back end if
the connection to them was reused.
So this means you have to reuse the
connection to the front end in order to
like find the vulnerability.
Okay.
>> Oh jeez. And
that's where that's why I called the
post
the where the false false positive
because it looks like a false positive
but it might actually not be a false
positive right. Uh so in the post I
share some strategies for how to
identify this kind of request smuggling
vulnerability which I refer to as
connection locked vulnerabilities and
you can do some funky stuff with timing
and I made a custom action for Burpuite
that you can run and it will try and
tell you if it's pipelining or if it's a
real vulnerability but it's still kind
of guessing so it won't be right 100% of
the time. Basically, if you want to
prove that you've got a connection
locked request smuggling, you need to
elicit a response from the server
>> with the smuggle second request that you
cannot elicit directly.
>> That's that's the that's the proof
because the power of the attack is it
lets you do things like like cash
poisoning. It lets you bypass front end
header rewrites. It lets you send, you
know, malformed host headers that might
get blocked by the front end and so on.
So that's what to start looking for if
you see this behavior.
>> Yeah, it's quite advanced. That's kind
of that's kind of what I was thinking
with this is like you know just thinking
outside of request smuggling like can we
use HTTP pipelining to bypass
if if things like getting headers
stripped out or something like that you
know is something going to be looking at
that TCP stream and be like oh
>> this is an HTTP request that that's
allowed let the whole TCP stream through
and then but that actually contains two
HTTP requests. Okay, so this is it's
even more there's kind of two different
things here.
Uh what I was just talking about you you
need a desync for that to work right
like there is a desync it's just not a
desync that's exploitable to affect
other connections but and yeah if you
can do that you can bypass front end
security spoof headers do cool stuff.
>> Mhm.
But the attack that like if you just do
pipelining like with like normal HP
requests on a server that doesn't have a
desync. Well, some servers do in fact
treat the first request on a given
connection differently.
Uh so I call this a connection state
attack. Uh and one common one like the
most common one that I've seen in the
wild is called first request routting.
Basically, they look at your first
request host header to see where which
back end to send the request to and then
they send all the subsequent requests on
that connection to the same back end.
>> So, that's amazing for doing host header
attacks like password reset poisoning.
>> That's a really good Yeah,
>> it's nice James.
>> It's nice and I'm going to release a
custom action that supports this in
about a month's time, but we have to add
a feature to Buete to make it possible.
But it's on the way. Wow, dude. That's
really cool. Um,
yeah, I I think that is a really
interesting way to approach this because
the I knew that pipelining pipeline was
just giving me weird vibes. Like I'm
sure that there's something that's just
looking at
a portion of the this the data and then
just sort of yeeting it all down into
the same, you know, TCP connection and
stream. Um, so there what you're saying
is that there definitely are servers
that are looking at the first request in
a in a stream and making decisions based
off of that.
>> Yes. Yes. Generally, if you want the
attack that any kind of weird attack to
have the best chance of success, put it
on the second request on the connection.
Uh, in practice, that's super clunky
right now, but we're shipping an update
which is going to fix that.
>> Wow. Wow. There's going to be a button
and you press the button and it sends
your repeater request, but it smuggles
it behind like a nice looking request.
>> That's That's pretty cool. That is
pretty sweet. Um, James, this has been
amazing, man. This has been a lot of
really awesome information. Thank you so
much for coming on the pod. Did you have
anything else you wanted to sort of
shout out or mention before we close?
>> Uh, no. Thanks. It's been great to be on
here.
>> Yeah, dude. Frick. One of my favorite
episodes ever. That GG, dude. GG. Good
pod. And that's a wrap on this episode
of Critical Thinking. Thanks so much for
watching to the end, y'all. If you want
more critical thinking content, uh, or
if you want to support the show, head
over to ctbb.show/isord.
You can hop in the community. There's
lots of great highlevel hacking
discussion happening there on top of
master classes, hackalongs, exclusive
content, and a full-time hunters guild.
If you're a full-time hunter, it's a
great time. Trust me. All right, I'll
see you there.